And that's when the yellow birdie thought to himself, "Hmm. My favorite little tree isn't such a little tree anymore."
So she sang her song, big and strong, and they all lived in that great, big tree happily ever after. The... End.
Applejack! Were you reading a bedtime story to... An apple tree?
Well, ya know, being replanted in a whole new place is very upsettin' for a tree...
And Bloomberg here is one of my favorites.
No fair, Applejack! You've got a luxurious, private sleeper car for a tree,
while I am crowded and cramped in the same car with all the other ponies.
How am I supposed to get my beauty sleep?!
But Bloomberg's the whole reason we're makin' this trip.
He needs his rest so we can give him as a gift to my relatives in Appleloosa.
You talk about it as if it's your baby or something.
Who you calling a baby?! Bloomberg's no baby!
Don't wet widdle Rarity make you all saddy-waddy. Bloomberg's a big and strong apple tree. Yes, he is.
It's widdle Rarity who's all saddy-waddy!
Oh man, we're going fast! This is so exciting I can't even wait!
For crying out loud in the morning!
Do you guys mind? I was up early fire-roasting those snacks you're all eating, and I'm pooped!
Speaking of, some of these popcorn kernels didn't get popped.
Okay, fine...
Good Night!
Maybe it's time we all got a little shut-eye. We've got a big day ahead of us tomorrow.
Pinkie Pie, you asleep yet?
No, are you asleep yet?
If I was sleeping, how could I have asked you if you were asleep?
Oh yeah!
When we get to Appleloosa, you think we'll have to carry that heavy tree all the way from the train to the orchard?
What tree? You mean Bloomberg?
No... Fluttershy.
Fluttershy's not a tree, silly!
What's going on?
Rainbow Dash thinks Fluttershy's a tree!
I do not think she's a tree! I was just...
Did you say she was a tree?
No. Well.. Yes. But not exactly...
Ya know she's not a tree, right?
She's not a tree, Dashy!
I'd like to be a tree!
For pete's sake!
Well that was kind of huffy.
Huffy the magic dragon!
Would you all be QUIET... NOOOOW!!!
Bloomberg?
Bloomberg!
Sorry, but I tend to snore a bit. Good night.
A buffalo stampede!
I just love their accessories!
They're getting awfully close to the train.
Oh, looky! Now they're doing TRICKS!
Now do a back-flip!
Or... Just jump?
Something tells me this isn't a circus act.
Hey there! Where ya headed in such a hurry?
Wow, you're pretty quick for someone so... Bulky... No offense.
I just wanna know...
I'm talking to you...
I got you now, you ...
They've got Bloomberg!
Heeeelp!
And Spike!
Heeelp!
Dragon-napping Spike. I'll show her!
Hey there! Welcome ta Applelooosa!
Braeburn, listen...
Cousin Apple Jack, mind yer manners, you have yet ta introduce me to your compadres! Shame on you!
Braeburn, listen, something terrible has happened....
Terrible is right, your train is full seven minutes late!
That's seven minutes less for you to delight in the pleasures and wonders of... Applelooosa!
Boggles the mind, we settler ponies built all this in just the past year, don't it?!
And as you can see, we have all of the finest comforts. Like horse-drawn carriages!
- Okay, you pull now.
- Aww, we just switched.
And those there are horse-drawn, horse-drawn carriages.
Listen, Braeburn, I...
And here's are local waterin' hole, the Salt Block.
That's enough salt for you!!
Can't I at least... Get a glass of water?
Over there's the office of Sheriff Silverstar.
And here's where we have out wild west dances!
And here's where we have out mild west dances!
But, Braeburn, we...
And here's the most wonderful sight in all of... Applelooosa! Our apple orchard.
- Braeburn!
- First harvest should be any day now.
- Good thing too!
- Brae...
- 'cause we need that grub to live on.
Braeburn!
Yes, cuz?
You have a very nice town an' all, but but we have a HUGE problem! Some of our friends are missing!
- A stampede of buffalo.
- They took Spike!
- Rainbow Dash went after them!
- And we can't find Pinkie Pie.
And we had an apple tree with us for your orchard, but they took that too!
Did you say... Buffalo?
Them buffalo, they want us settler ponies to take every single tree you see here off this land.
They sure as hay don't want any new ones added in.
But why?
Beats me. We put a lot of hard work into this land, so we can feed our town, our families, our foals!
And now they're saying all these trees have to go? It ain't fair...
I can't wait to get my hooves on that little buffalo...
- Nobody tricks Rainbow Dash and gets away with it.
- Boo!!
Pinkie Pie!
You caught me! Looks like I tricked you and didn't get away with it either! You're goood.
What do you think you're doing?! You gotta get out of here!
I do?
You're gonna blow my cover.
I am?
I'm trying to save Spike!
Oh my gosh, so am I!
And the more of us there are out here, the more chances of us getting...
... caught.
Run, Pinkie, I'll hold 'em off. Save yourself!
Stop!
Dash, Pinkie... 'Sup? Hey, no worries I know those guys.
- They're cool.
- If you say so, Spike. Catch ya later, bro.
Seems they took me by mistake.. And they feel awful about it, too, poor guys.
Fortunately, they totally respect dragons, so they treat me like an honored guest.
Still don't like ponies much, though... But you're with me, so it's cool.
Well, I still don't trust them. I say we turn tail and bail while we still...
Before we finish eating? Are you loco in the coco?!
Can I please have more of that mushy stuff, whatever it was?
Certainly.
And, Mr. Spike, you like gemstones, yes?
Turquoise.
This here is Little Strongheart, and these are my friends Pinkie Pie and Rainbow Dash.
- You!
That's it! We are outta here!
Wait! Please accept my apologies for what happened on the train, we didn't mean for anyone to be hurt.
Yeah, right.
We only wanted the tree. The settler ponies have overtaken the land and have planted an orchard all over it!
Because of their thoughtlessness, we can no longer run over our traditional stampeding grounds...
I think it's time they met Chief Thunderhooves.
We have a long and winding stampeding trail, that we have run upon for many generations.
My father stampeded upon these grounds, and his father before him, and his father before him, and his father before him.
And his father before him. And...
I think they get the idea, Chief.
It is a sacred tradition to run the path every year.
But this year, these... Settler ponies, these... Appleloosians!
They planted apple trees all over it without asking our permission.
Well that's not very nice. Right, Rainbow Dash?
The ponies refused to move their trees, so we are stuck here, and it is not fair!
See Rainbow Dash? They had a good reason to...
I'll say they had a good reason!
C'mon. We have some apple-pickin' Appleloosians to talk to!
Gently, please!
Sorry, Rarity, but our friends are out there and we have ta be ready for a long hike
into buffalo territory if we're gonna save 'em.
Let's go!
- Hi guys!
- Pinkie!
We're so glad you're safe.
- Oh, there you are!
- Thank goodness!
How did you escape from the buffalo?
We didn't!
We promised the buffalo a chance to talk.
Oh, yeah? 'Bout what?
We brought our new pal, Little Strongheart here, to explain to the Appleloosians
why they should move the apple trees off buffalo land.
That information would be quite help...
That's weird. 'cause my cousin, Braeburn, here, wants to explain to the buffalo why they should let the apple trees stay.
That would be a useful thing to...
The land is theirs! You planted the trees not knowing that. Honest mistake. Now, you just gotta move 'em, that's all.
Well...
They busted their rumps here! An' now they're suppos't ta bust their rumps again, just 'cause some buffalo won't stampede someplace else?
Plant the trees somewhere else!
Where?! It's the only flatland around these parts!
The buffalo had it first!
The settler ponies need it to LIVE!
- Come on Applejack!
- You're bein' unreasonable!
Look. Both the settlers and the buffalo have good reasons to use this land.
There must be something we can do.
Hey! I've got an idea!
We may be divided
But of you all, I beg
To remember we're all hoofed
At the end of each leg
No matter what the issue
Come from wherever you please
All this fighting gets you nothing
But hoof-in-mouth disease
Arguing's not the way
Hey, come out and play
It's a shiny, new day
So what do you say?
You gotta share, you gotta care
It's the right thing to do
And there'll always be a way through
Both our diets, I should mention
Are completely vegetarian
We all eat hay and oats
Why be at each other's throat?
You gotta share, you gotta care
It's the right thing to do
And there'll always be a way throuuuuuuugh
All right, Pinkie Pie! That was fantastic! What a great song! You're right on!!
It appears that Sheriff Silverstar and I have come to... An agreement.
We have.
That was the worst performance we've ever seen...
Absolutely.
The time for action... is upon us! Our stampede will start at high noon tomorrow.
And if the orchard is still there, we'll flatten IT! AND the whole town!
But, Chief!
An' we Appleloosians say you'd better bring yer best, 'cause we'll be ready and waitin'.
But, Sheriff...
Oh... That wasn't the message of my song at all...
I want my kin ta have what they need to live... But a storm's a-brewin' here.
And I don't like the look of it.
We've just got to talk some sense into them before somepony gets hurt.
Listen, maybe if you would just reconsider, we...
About the trees. Now if you could...
If we could just sit down and talk we could...
Why won't anybody be rational and reasonable?!
Sheriff, if we could only...
Isn't there someway to stop this?
Unless the settlers remove those trees, I do not think so.
I know you don't want to do this.
But they have taken out land. What would you have me do, Rainbow Dash?
I don't know... But it's never too late to think of something.
At noon, it will be too late.
Come on, THINK. Think, think, think, think, think, think, think!
He's not gonna do it!
You got to share, you got to care
It's the right thing to do
Charge!
Ready?
Aim...
Fire!
I've got a much better idea!
We... Will allow the apple orchard to stay in exchange for a share of it's fruit. Those... Delicious apple pies!
I'd rather eat turquoise any day of the week.
Bloomberg, this is yer special day. Mama's so proud of you!
Dear, Princess Celestia. Friendship is a wonderous and powerful thing.
Even the worst of enemies can become friends. You need understanding and compromise.
You've got to share. You've got to care
Hé! That's what I said!