Spike, wake up. Wake up, wake up, it's Winter Wrap Up day!
- Huh? Mommy?
- Winter Wrap Up!
You're not mommy.
Spike, the first day of spring is tomorrow, so every pony in Ponyville needs to clean up winter. Now help me get ready.
Clean up winter? Who cleans up winter? Don't they just use magic to change the seasons like they do in Canterlot?
No Spike, Ponyville was started by earth ponies, so for hundreds of years they've never used magic to clean up winter.
It's traditional.
It's ridiculous. No magic... Fuh.
Okay, let's see: scarf, check; saddle, check; boots, check; Spike refusing to get up and going back to sleep, check. It's a good thing I'm so organized, I'm ready. Bright and early.
Oh... maybe a little too early.
Those must be the team vests Rarity designed.
Blue for the weather team, green for the plant team, and tan for the animal team. I wonder which team vest I'll be wearing.
I'll take a blue vest, same color as my blanket, which I think I hear calling my name.
"Spike! Spike! Come to bed!"
Ugh, it's too early.
Thank you everypony, for being here bright and early. We need every single pony's help to wrap up winter, and bring in spring.
Now, all of you have your vests, and have been assigned to your teams, so let's do even better than last year, and have the quickest Winter Wrap Up ever!
Oh, this is so exciting.
Alright everypony, find your team leader... and let's get galloping!
Oh gosh, where should I go? I'm not sure where I fit in.
What exactly does everypony do?
Three months of winter coolness
And awesome holidays
We've kept our hoofsies warm at home
Time off from work to play
But the food we've stored is runnin' out
And we can't grow in this cold
And even though I love my boots
This fashion's getting old.
The time has come to welcome spring
And all things warm and green
But it's also time to say goodbye
It's winter we must clean
How can I help? I'm new, you see
What does everypony do?
How do I fit in without magic?
I haven't got a clue.
Winter Wrap Up! Winter Wrap Up!
Let's finish our holiday cheer
'cause tomorrow spring is here
'cause tomorrow spring is here...
Bringing home the southern birds
A pegasus's job begins
And clearing all the gloomy skies
To let the sunshine in
We move the clouds
And we melt the white snow
When the sun comes up
Its warmth and beauty will glow
Winter Wrap Up! Winter Wrap Up!
Let's finish our holiday cheer
'cause tomorrow spring is here
Little critters hibernate
Under the snow and ice
We wake up all the sleepy heads
So quietly and nice
We help them gather up their food
Fix their homes below
We welcome back the southern birds
So their families can grow
Winter Wrap Up! Winter Wrap Up!
Let's finish our holiday cheer
'cause tomorrow spring is here
No easy task to clear the ground
Plant our tiny seeds
With proper care and sunshine
Everyone it feeds
Apples, carrots, celery stalks
Colorful flowers too
We must work so very hard
It's just so much to do
Winter Wrap Up! Winter Wrap Up!
Let's finish our holiday cheer
'cause tomorrow spring is here
Now that I know what they all do
I have to find my place
And help with all of my heart
Tough task ahead I face
How will I do without my magic
Help the earth pony way
I want to belong so I must
Do my best today
Winter Wrap Up! Winter Wrap Up!
Let's finish our holiday cheer
'cause tomorrow spring is here
Winter Wrap Up! Winter Wrap Up!
'cause tomorrow spring is here!
Everypony belongs to a team. What should I do? Where should I go?
Alright team, you're clear for takeoff.
Rainbow Dash!
Oh, hey Twilight, what's up?
What are you doing?
Sending off one of my flight crews to retrieve the birds that have flown south for the winter.
Oh, can I help? How about if I help clear out the clouds?
Right. No wings.
Sorry Twilight.
Great, now what do we do?
I don't know about you, but I'm gonna be nappin'.
Come on Spike, this is serious business. Winter needs to be wrapped up, and I'm determined to do my part.
Somehow...
Rarity, please tell me there's something, anything I can help you with.
Well, how would you like to help create Ponyville's finest birds' nests?
Birds' nests?
Why yes. When the weather team guides the birds back north for the spring, they'll need a place to live and lay their eggs.
Wow Rarity, that one's really beautiful.
Oh why, thank you most sincerely. Would you like to try your hoof at a nest?
Would I? Yes! Where do I begin?
Okay. Now... uh, take some of that straw and hay over there, and a little bit of branch.
Now, weave them through there, yes. Uh, take some ribbon, yes, oh uh, n... not there, oooh, yes, uh, tuck it in over there, uh but be careful not to...
I don't know I guess that would do... oh dear.
There!
It looks just like... yours. Oh my.
That nest needs to be condemned.
Oh, Spa-ha-hike, it's not so bad, ah, maybe birds can use it as a...
An outhouse?
Spike. It's just fine. It's just a little rough around the edges.
Let me lend you a hoof. Let's just untie this ribbon, and let me take out these sticks here, we'll shave this...
I think we lost her.
- Helooooooo Twilight! Wheeeeeeee!
- Wow Pinkie Pie, you're quite the skater. Probably the best skater I've ever seen.
Thanks Twilight, I've been doing this since I was an itty-bitty little-wittle Twinkie-Pinkie.
Just comes naturally.
Which is probably why they designated me the lake scorer.
I cut lines in the lakes with my skates. That way, when the rest of the weather team comes here to break the ice, it'll be easy as pie.
How clever. When the thick ice begins to melt, it'll break along the lines.
Well you sure have a lot of work ahead of you, there's quite a few lakes in Ponyville.
Ha, tell me about it. Hey, Twilight, wanna help me out?
- Would I?
- Come on, put on those skates over there. I bet you'll be a natural too.
Okay.
Uh... maybe on second thought.
- What are you talking about? You said you wanted to be helpful.
- Yippie!
Now get out there.
Twilight, steer! Steer!
Oh boy...
Ha ha, you are a natural, Twilight. A natural disaster.
Twilight, you did a great job your first time around. I'm sure my first time was just as wobbly and bobbly and crasheriffic as yours.
Really?
No.
But did I make you feel better?
Mm-hmm, yeah, I guess.
I think you'll be super awesome at something that keeps your hoofs on the ground. I know, Fluttershy could probably use your help with the critters.
Well... I'm pretty good with little animals. Yeah, I'll go help her.
Uh... it's, ah, that a-way.
Wake up little sleepy heads. Hope you had some wonderful dreams and restful hibernation, but it's time to get up now, spring is coming.
Awww, how cute.
Aren't they? This is my favorite task the whole season, when I get to see all my little animal friends again.
Uh, what's "hibernation"?
It's like a long sleep.
Long sleep?
Yes.
Wake up little porcupines.
Animals often hibernate through the winter to save their energy and eat less food.
I definitely like the idea of hibernation, uh, except for the "eat less food" part.
Oh, but just look at all these warrens and dens, I'm worried that I won't be able to wake up every animal before spring comes.
Well, I'll help, Fluttershy.
You will? Oh, that would be wonderful.
Okay, let's start there.
Hello? Wake up little friends, wherever you are. Spring is coming.
I wonder which cute little furry creatures I've awoken.
Waaa! Snakes! Snakes!
Good morning friends.
All this Winter Wrap Up stuff is a lot harder than it looks.
Right, because there's no magic. Why don't you just use magic, Twilight, and get it done the right way?
No, Spike, I have to do it the traditional way. Ponyville has never needed magic to wrap up winter.
Well, they never had you here before, either. Think how much quicker they could wrap up winter with your magic.
No, no, no!
I'm gonna find some other way that I can help out if it kills me.
Keep pushin', Caramel. That's it pumpkin', I know it's hard work, but you guys are doin' great. Yee-haw!
Hey Applejack. How's everything going?
Oh, just dandy. Little slow startin', but peachy all the same.
There's a lot of ground to clear ya hear. We can't even start the plantin' and the waterin' until we git all these heap a' snow high-tailed outta here.
Well, I'd like to help.
- Well, I... I dunno Twilight.
- Just give me a chance!
Well, I never turn down a hard worker but...
Think of how much quicker they could wrap up winter with your magic.
I could use a come-to-life spell. Hwww... Here goes...
Hmm. She's awful strong for such a little pony.
- That's my girl, following my advice.
- And what in tarnation does that mean?
Uh oh. Slow down. Slow down!
What's going on? Wha'd'ya do? You used magic, didn't you?
- Nuts Twilight, you used magic.
- The nerve. Can you believe her?
That's not how we do it 'round here, Twilight, and especially not on MAH farm.
Well, see, I just wanted to...
Come on, Twilight. Come on out.
I'm a winter mess up.
Well you're good at a lot of things, just not nest-making, ice-skating, animal-waking, snow-clearing.
Thanks a lot for making me feel so much better.
That's what I'm here for, sister.
Rainbow Dash, y'all on the weather team need to melt the rest of the snow here on the ground and the trees, pronto.
- Got it.
- Wait. My poor little animals' homes will get flooded if the snow melts too fast.
- I'm tellin' you Rainbow, you gotta melt that snow now.
No, you simply must wait.
- Okay.
- Go.
- Stop!
- Go!
Ugh! Make up your minds!
Oh! What in Equestria are all you arguing about?
This sort of silliness is why we were late for spring last year, and the year before that, and the year before that.
Did she say late?
I was hoping my amazingly inspirational speech would urge everyone to do better than last year
but now it looks like we're going to be later than ever.
I mean just look at this catastrophe. The ice scorers made the ice chunks too big to melt;
the nest designer is horrendously behind, we need several hundred, and she's only made one;
And don't get me started on all the clouds in the sky, the icicles on the trees... This isn't good, not at all!
And it's gonna be all to pieces disastrous if we can't get our seeds all planted.
Chillax Applejack, we're bustin' our chops as fast as we can.
No, not fast, we have to wake animals slowly.
Uh, AJ?
Oh good gravy, Caramel lost the grass seeds again, didn't he?
Ai-yup.
Ditzy Doo accidentally went north to get the southern birds!
Oh that featherbrain. Didn't she learn her lesson last year when she went west?
Stop this at once. We don't have time to argue.
It's almost sundown. Spring is going to be late again.
Another year of scandal and shame. If only we could be more organized.
Spike! Get my checklist and clipboard, STAT!
Yes ma'am.
Stop everypony.
Stop.
Sorry.
I know you all want to complete your jobs on time, but arguing is no way to go about it. What you need is...
organization. And I'm just the pony for the job.
I can't believe it. Spring is here! On time!
- And we have you to thank for it. If it weren't for your organizing skills we would still be arguing.
- Ai-yup.
It was a team effort.
And since you helped every team, we have an official vest for you. We give you the title, "All-Team Organizer".
Gosh, I don't even know what to say. Thank you everypony.
And hereby I declare that winter is... wrapped up on time.
Spike's sure gonna be in for a hog-sized surprised when that last piece a' ice melts.
Dear Princess Celestia,
Winter Wrap Up was one of the most special things I've ever been a part of here in Ponyville.
It helped me to learn we all have hidden talents, and if we're patient and diligent, we're sure to find them
and as always, with good friendship and teamwork, ponies can accomplish anything.
How's that, Spike? Spike?
Oh, Spike.