Perfect.
Just take the broken limbs down, Rarity.
Don'tcha all care about nothing other than prettifyin'?
Somepony has to. You were making an absolute mess of the town square, Applejack.
Yeah, well, the storm's gonna make an even bigger mess
if we don't prune all these loose branches so they don't tumble down on anypony.
I simply cannot imagine why the pegasus ponies would schedule a dreadful downpour this evening
and ruin what could have been a glorious sunny day.
Think more practical-like, will ya?
They accidentally skipped a scheduled sprinkle last week,
so we need a doozy of a downpour to make up for it, is all.
Oh no! My wonderfully styled mane shall be ruined!
Ya shoulda hurried up and finished the job already.
It's coming down too fast!
Help me!
There. Hunker down to your heart's content whilst I finish this.
Oh, no, no, no!
What now?
I prefer not to get my hooves muddy.
There is just no pleasin' ya, is there?
Everything's got to be just so.
Well, and how does muddying my hooves serve any useful purpose?
Y'all wouldn't know useful if it came up and bit cha.
That doesn't even make any sense.
- Does so.
- Does not.
- Does so infinity.
- Does not infinity plus one.
What say we go our separate ways before one of us says something she will regret.
I reckon y'all're gonna say something you'll regret first.
On the contrary. I belive it shall most certainly be you who says something you will regret first.
- I'm not sayin' anythin'.
- Nor am I.
- Y'all just be on yer way, then.
- After you!
Perhaps we should stick together for now and find some shelter.
Perhaps we should.
Sounds fair.
Nice and dry under here, sort'a.
Unacceptable.
Applejack! Rarity!
Twilight?
Come inside, girls, quick.
Whoa, Nelly. Is inside a tree really the best place to be in a lightning storm?
It is if you have a magical lightning rod protecting your home like I do.
Come on in!
We are most grateful for your invitation.
Thank ya kindly for your hospitality.
Do be a polite houseguest and go wash up please, won't you?
If I gotta stand one more second with that fussbudget Rarity today,
I can't be held responsible for what I'm gonna do.
Some storm, huh? The pegasus ponies sure have outdone themselves this time.
I hope you and Applejack don't have any trouble getting home.
It may indeed be a problem.
Well, you're welcome to stay if need be.
Spike is away in Canterlot on royal business. I'm all alone tonight.
You and Applejack should totally sleep over! We'll have a slumber party!
I've always wanted one of those.
Goodness. Uh, I do believe I have another engagement scheduled for this evening that completely slipped my mind until just now.
Silly me, I can't possibly stay here all night... with Applejack.
Slumber 101: All You've Ever Wanted to Know About Slumber Parties But Were Afraid to Ask.
My own personal copy. It's a fantastic reference guide. You should see the table of contents.
I've been waiting for a chance to use it, and today is the day! This is gonna be so great!
Yes, uh, great.
What in tarnation...
Now wait just a goll-darn minute. Ya make me wash the mud off my hooves, but it's okay for y'all ta have mud all over your faces?
Silly! This is called a mud mask. It's to refresh and rejuvinate your complexion.
We're giving each other makeovers!
We have to do it, it says so in the book.
Slumber 101: Everything You...
Oh hey, heh, would ya look at the time. I gotta skidaddle on home quick. I'm powerful late for, uh, fer somethin'.
Good night.
Or maybe I'll stay here for a spell.
Hurray slumber party!
What in the world is this for?
To reduce the puffiness around one's eyes, of course.
Puffiness-schmuffiness!
That's good eatin'!
Isn't this exciting? We'll do everything by the book
and that will make my slumber party officially fun.
Did you hear that, Applejack? You certainly would not want to do anything that would ruin Twilight's very first slumber party, would you?
Of course not, 'n you wouldn't either, I reckon.
So do we have an agreement?
You betcha.
Gross!
You know, there's messy and there's just plain rude.
You know, there's fussy 'n there's just plain gettin' on my nerves.
Fortunately, I can get along with anypony, no matter how difficult she may be.
Oh yeah? Well, I'm the get-alongin'ist pony your ever gonna meet.
That's not even a word.
This is going to be the bestest slumber party ever! Yay!
Yay.
So, how are you getting along over there, Applejack?
Just fine, Rarity.
This is so awesome! Makeovers, check.
It says here we have to tell ghost stories. Who wants to go first?
Me!
I'd like to tell y'all the terrifying tale of the prissy ghost who drove everypony crazy
with her unnecessary neatness.
I'm sure y'all are familiar with that one.
Never heard of it. I have a much better one.
It's the horrifying story of the messy, inconsiderate ghost who irritated every pony within a hundred miles!
That's not a real story. You made it up.
It is a ghost story, they're all made up.
I got one! This story is called The Legend of the Headless Horse.
It was a dark and stormy night, just like this one.
And three ponies were having a sumber party, just like this one.
...and just when the last pony thought she was safe, there, standing right behind her,
just inches away was...
the Headless Horse!
Ghost story, check.
Now, who wants s'mores?
Then you place one marshmallow on the top of the chocolate and be sure it's centered, that's critical,
and then carefully put another perfectly square graham cracker on the top.
And done. Ta-da!
Nah, ya just eat 'em.
You could at least say excuse me.
Aw, I was just about to, but you interrupted me.
Pardon.
S'mores, check.
Now the next item of fun we have to do is Truth or Dare.
I dare Applejack to do something carefully and neatly for a change.
Oh yeah? Well I dare Rarity to lighten up and stop obsessin' over every last little detail, for a change.
I think the truth of the matter is that some pony could stand to pay a little more attention to details.
And I think the truth is some pony oughta quit with her fussin'
so the rest of us can get things done.
I don't think this is how the game's supposed to work.
You have to give an honest answer to any question or do whatever any pony dares you to do.
I dare you to step outside and let your precious, tidy mane get ruined again.
You have to. It's the rule.
Fine!
Okay. I dare Applejack to play dress-up in a fru-fru, glittery, lacey outfit.
Happy?
Very.
Do I ever get a turn?
I dare ya to enter the next rodeo when it comes to town.
I dare you not to enter the next rodeo that comes to town.
I dare ya to not comb your mane a hundred times before bed.
And I dare you to comb yours just once.
I, uh, I think we should check off Truth or Dare and move on.
Let's see what our next fun-fun-fun thing is, shall we?
Hm, what does this mean? Pillow fight?
Oh, please. I am not at all interested in participating in something so crude.
Oh! It! Is! On!
Oh, I get it! Pillow, fight! Fun!
Girls, maybe we should take it down a notch?
I will if she will.
She started it.
Maybe we should just call it a night and get some sleep?
Keep your muddy hooves on your side of the bed.
My hooves ain't muddy.
They were. There might still be a little on them.
There ain't. See?
Now who's bein' inconsiderate?
I have to make the bed again so the blanket will be right. Get up.
You'll ruin it. You have to do it like this.
Yeah, that's not gonna happen.
Geronimo!
You did that on purpose.
Um... yeah.
Get up so I can fix it again.
Can't hear ya, I'm asleep.
I ain't budgin'.
You will if you want any blanket.
- Give it back!
- I will not!
- Yes, you will!
- Won't!
- Will!
Enough!
It says right here that the number one thing you're supposed to do at a slumber party is have fun,
and thanks to you two I can't check that off!
I've been tryin' my darndest to get along.
No, it is I who've been trying my best.
- No, it was me.
- No, it was I.
- Me!
- I!
I hope you're happy, both of you. You've ruined my very first slumber party.
The makeovers, the s'mores, Truth or Dare, the pillow fight...
I mean, is there anything else that could possibly go wrong?
Sorry I asked.
Ya see? That's why we needed to take down all those little branches in town, not spiffy 'em up.
- But I...
- Outta my way, missy! Time's a-wastin'.
Wait! Stop! Don't!
No watin'! No stopin'! Doin'!
And that, my friend, is what we call gettin' 'er done.
I tried to tell you it would come crashing down in here.
Well, ya shoulda tried harder.
I'm mighty sorry, Twilight.
It's... Well, it's not okay. There's a giant tree branch in the middle of my bedroom.
And the book doesn't say anything about having a giant tree branch at your slumber party.
Or at least I haven't found that entry yet. Ur... ah!
What in tarnation are y'all doin' over there?
Cleaning up this mess some pony made. Who was that again? Oh, right, that's you.
We gotta do somethin'.
Baking... BFFs... Brothers... There's nothing in here about branches.
Rarity, for pony's sake, stop sweatin' the small stuff and help me get rid of this thing!
I said hussle over here and help me!
Look, I'm sorry, all right?
What was that?
I said I'm sorry!
I shoulda listened to you when you noticed where this here branch would end up. Your annoyin' attention to detail
woulda saved us from this whole mess. But right now, ya need to stop bein' so dang fussy pickin' up
all those little things and help me move the one big thing in here that actually matters!
Please!
But I'll get all icky.
Consarnit! What the... eh... you... I mean, yes, ickiness is often a side effect of hard work.
But y'all need to get over it, on account I just can't fix this mess I made myself.
I need your help.
Let's do this.
Well, they do have a section about backyard slumber parties. Is that what we're doing right now? Does this count as camping?
Oh, I look awful.
Better?
Thanks.
Oh, pretty! Where did these come from?
They're not in the book either.
Is it bigger than a barn?
Nope.
Is it smaller than a saddle?
No! Only three of your twenty questions left!
We're never gonna guess what y'er thinkin' of, it could be anythin'.
Are we getting warmer?
Why? Is it too cold in here for you? I can turn up the heat.
She means are we gettin' any closer with our guesses?
No.
And that technically counts in as a question, so only two more left!
Is it... a six-legged pony with a purple polka-dotted mane and shootin' stars comin' out of his eyes?
Who flies through the air all over the world to hide magic, sparkly eggs?
That's it!
It is?
No.
It's that.
But it was just so nice to see you two finally getting along, I wanted you to be able to win together.
See? We could have been having fun like this all along.
If only some pony hadn't been so persnickety.
Well, maybe she wouldn't have been if some pony else hadn't been so sloppy.
Sorry for being such a pain in the patootie.
Oh, no, I'm sure I was much worse.
That's kind a ya ta say, but I'm the one who's sorry.
Oh, I'm much more sorry than you are.
- Are not.
- Are too.
- Are not!
I declare my first slumber party a success!
Have fun, check.
Now take two steps to your left. Uh, no, my left.
Which is it?
That mess is your fault, not mine.
Sorry.
Dear Princess Celestia,  it's hard to believe that two ponies who seem to have so little in common could
ever get along. But I found out that if you embrace each other's differences, you might just be surprised to discover
a way to be friends after all.
So, who's up for another slumber party tomorrow night?
How about a week from Thursday?
Oh, how about two weeks from Saturday?
A month from now?