Boy howdy! I got my work cut out for me.
That there is the biggest bumper crop a' apples I ever laid eyes on.
Ey-yup. Too big for you to handle on your own.
Come on, big brother! You need to rest up and get yourself better. I haven't met an apple orchard yet that I can't handle.
Oops, sorry.
I'll take a bite out of this job by day's end.
Biting off more than you can chew is just what I'm afraid of.
Are you sayin' my mouth is makin' promises my legs can't keep?
Yup.
Why of all the... This is your sister Applejack, remember? The loyalest of friends and the most dependable of ponies?
But still only one pony, and one pony plus hundreds o' apple trees just doesn't add up to...
Don't you use your fancy mathematics to muddle the issue!
I said I can handle this harvest and I'm gonna prove it to you.
I'm gonna get every last apple out of those trees this applebuck season all by myself.
Well I better get kickin'. These apples aren't gonna shake themselves outta the trees.
Hey!
Oh no.
STAMPEDE!
Hey...! Thiiis maaakes myyy voooice sooound siiilly!
Pinkie Pie, are you crazy?! Run!
Everypony calm down. There is no need to panic.
But Mayor, whatever shall we do?
Look there!
Move aside, Winona.
Put 'em up, girl!
This is the best rodeo show I've ever seen.
Come on, little doggies! Herd!
Winona, put 'em up!
Gotcha.
Attagirl.
Now what was that all about?
Oh my! Begging your pardon, Applejack, but Mooriella here saw one of those nasty snakes.
And it just gave us all the willies, dontcha know.
I completely understand. Just next time, try and steer clear of Ponyville.
We certainly will, Applejack. So long, Winona!
Ride 'em, cowpony!
Applejack was just... just...
Appletastic!
Exactly.
We must do something to thank Applejack for single-hoofedly saving the town.
I know.
A party!
We all ready?
Just one last thing.
Now we're ready.
Is Applejack all set?
Actually, I haven't seen her all week.
Not since the stampede.
But she'll be here for sure. Applejack is never late.
Welcome everypony!
Today we are here to honor a pony we can always count on to help in matters great and small.
A pony whose contributions to...
Did you see Applejack's slick moves out there? What an athlete.
This week she's gonna help me with my new flying trick, and I know it's gonna be so awesome.
Exactly. And...
This week, I get to run SugarCube Corner for the first time.
What does that have to do with Applejack?
Oh. Applejack, one of the best bakers ever, is gonna help me.
Applejack makes everything great, so free samples for everypony!
Oh-kay, that's great. Now if I could just make a point without being inter...
Twilight?
...-rupted.
Twilight, I'm so sorry, but I just wanted to mention that Applejack is also helping me this week with the official bunny census,
where we count up all the new baby bunnies that were born this season.
She's gonna help gather them using her wonderful herding skills.
Anyone else?
Anyone?
No?
Well then, as I was trying to say.
Nevermind.
And so, with no further ado, it is my privilege to give the prize, Pony of Ponyville Award, to our beloved guest of honor,
a pony of the utmost trustworthiness, reliability, and integrity. Ponyville's most capable and dependable friend:
Applejack!
Cool! Way to go Applejack, that was awesome! I mean, heh.
Awkward.
I'm here.
Sorry I'm late, whoa, I was just...
Did I get your tail?
Miss Mayor. Thank you kindly for this here... award thingy.
It's so bright and shiny and...
and sure do look funny heh.
Okay.
Well, thank you Applejack for saving us from that scary stampede,
and always being there for everypony.
Yeah. I like helping the ponyfolks and... and stuff.
Oh, uh, yeah. Uh, tshanks.
Was it just me, or did Applejack seem a little...
- Tired?
- Dizzy?
Messy?
Well, did you see her mane?
She seemed fine to me.
What on Earth is that pony doing?
Hey Applejack!
Applejack!
Howdy Twilight.
What is all this?
It's Applebuck season.
Applewhat season?
It's what the Apple family calls harvestin' time. We gather all the apples from the trees so we can sell 'em.
But why are you doing it all alone?
'cause Big Macintosh hurt himself.
What about all those relatives I've met when I first came to Ponyville? Can't they help?
They were just here for the Apple family reunion.
They actually live all over Equestria and are busy harvestin' their own orchards.
So, uh, I'm on my own.
Which means, I should really get back to work.
Hint hint? Get back to work?
Fine.
Could you step aside, Twilight?
I just did.
Applejack, you don't look so good.
Don't any a' you three worry none, I'm just fine and dandy.
Do you want some help?
Help? No way, no how.
But there's no way you can do it all on your own.
Is that a challenge?
Uhm... no?
Well, I'm gonna prove to you that I can do it! Now if you'll excuse me, I've got apples to buck.
There you are.
I'm a might' sorry, Rainbow.
I was busy applebuckin' and I guess ah, I closed my eyes for a second and, when I woke up, I was late.
Now, what's this new trick of yours?
See this contraption?
Yeah
Well, I'm gonna stand on one end, then you're gonna jump down from that platform,
launching me into the air faster than I can take off on my own.
Once I'm in the air, I'm gonna do some amazing flips and spins that are sure to impress the Wonderbolts.
Isn't that a might' dangerous?
Not for a pony who can fly.
Well, alrighty then.
Oh my.
Ready? One... two... THREE!
Maybe I wasn't clear. You're supposed to land on the other end.
Got it.
Applejack, what the hay is going on? I mean, I thought I was working with Ponyville's best athlete!
You are. I'm okay. Really. I have an idea. Watch this.
Maybe not. Okay, one more try. I'm sure to get it this time.
Here I go!
Wait, Applejaaaaack!
You're welcome!
Can I help you?
I think somepony else needs your help.
- Applejack?
- Yep.
Applejack, can we talk?
CAN BEES SQUAWK?! I DON'T THINK SO.
No! Can we talk?
TWENTY STALKS? BEAN OR CELERY?
No! I need to talk to you.
YOU NEED TO WALK TO THE ZOO? WELL, WHO'S STOPPIN' YOU?
I need to talk to you!
OH! WELL WHY DIDN'T YOU SAY SO? WHAT YOU WANNA TALK ABOUT?
Rainbow Dash dropped in to see me today.
THAT'S QUITE NEIGHBORLY OF HER.
YES, EXCEPT THAT SHE CRASHED ONTO MY BALCONY AFTER YOU LAUNCHED HER INTO THE AIR.
Oh, yeah. I wasn't feeling quite myself this morning.
Because you're working too hard and you need help.
WHAT? KELP? I don't need kelp. I don't even like seaweed.
HELP! YOU NEED HELP!
Nothin' doin', Twilight. I'm gonna prove to you, to everypony, that I can do this on my own.
Now if you'll excuse me, I've gotta go help Pinkie Pie.
Now Pinkie Pie, are you sure you're up for baking the muffins and running the store this afternoon?
Yes siree bob, Mrs Cake. Plus, I have Ponyville's prized pony to help me out.
Why, she's the best baker ever. Right, Applejack?
No? You're not the best baker ever?
WHAT? Oh no!
I mean, don't you fret. I can bake anything from fritters to pies in the blink of an eye.
Alright. Wuh, see you later, girls!
Stop with the shakin', it's time to get bakin'.
Alrighty! I'll get the sugar and the eggs. Can you get me some chocolate chips?
Chat was that?
What was that?
Chocolate chips.
Chips... got it.
Tater chips, all salty and dry, okie-dokie.
What next?
Baking soda.
Soda. Perfect. That'll get the tater chips nice and wet.
Now what?
A cup of flour.
A cup of sour? Well, lemons are sure sour.
One cup of sour, comin' up.
Anything else, Pinkie?
One last thing. Wheat germ.
Wheat worms? Oh, that must be fancy talk for earthworms.
Now that's gonna be delicious.
If you say so.
Free muffin sample spectacular!
Yeah! Muffin spectacles! Get 'em while they're hot.
We came as soon as we heard.
Oh thank you, Twilight. We need all the help we can get.
Oh no! What happened?
It was a mishap with some of the baked goods.
No, not baked goods, baked bads.
Applejack!
Want one?
What? Huh?
Applejack, we need to talk.
It's you, Twilight. I know what you're gonna say, but the answer is still no.
Not to upset your applecart, but you need help.
Hardy har. No I don't.
Here, let me help.
Help? No thanks.
A little more... Little...
There.
I'll prove that this apple can handle these apples.
Come on... apples... fall off.
AJ, think you're beating a dead... tree.
I knew that.
Actually Applejack, I had something else to talk to you about. I just came back from Ponyville Urgent Care and...
You know, I'm a little busy to get lectured right now, Twilight.
But if you'd just let me help...
No, no, NO! How many times do I gotta say it?
I don't need no help from nopony!
That pony is stubborn as a mule.
No offense.
None taken.
Oh Applejack! Thank you so much for offering your herding skills for the annual rabbit round up.
Why are we doin' this?
Well, lots of new baby bunnies have been born, so it's my job to get a count of all the new families.
Fine. Can we just get on with it?
Certainly, but remember, these are bunnies we're dealing with, not cows.
They're a timid bunch and need to be treated gently.
I do NOT need any direction on corrallin' critters. Right, Winona?
Okay, little bunnies! I need you to all gathered here in the middle.
That's right! Let's go, bunnies. In the center. Hop to it.
Swell. Just swell.
Put 'em up, Winona!
Applejack! Winona! Stop! You're scaring them.
We know what we're doin'. Get along, little bunnies.
Oh no.
STAMPEDE!
The horror, the horror.
- It was awful.
- A disaster. A horrible, horrible disaster.
I don't get it.
Our gardens, destroyed.
Every last flower, devoured.
By... by... THEM!
Oh my. Oh... Please stop, little bunnies. Oh no! Please, let's go home. Oh my goodness.
Alright. Enough is enough.
Must... keep... buckin'... just... a few... more. Must finish harvestin'.
Alright, Applejack. Your applebucking hasn't just caused you problems,
it's over-propelled pegasus', practically poisoned plenty of ponies,
and terrorized bushels of brand new bouncing baby bunnies.
I don't care what you say, you. Need. Help.
Ha! No I don't. Look, ah did it.
I harvested the entire Sweet Apple Acres without your help. How d'ya like them apples?
Um, how do you like them apples?
Where'd all the apple...?
Applejack? Applejack!
Oh, good, you're okay.
Now Applejack, I completely respect the Apple family ways.
You're always there to help any pony in need,
so maybe you can put a little of your stubborn pride aside and allow your friends to help you?
- Okay, Twilight.
- I am not taking "no" for an answer... what?
Yes, Twilight. Yes. Please. I could really use your help.
Dear Princess Celestia, my friend Applejack is the best friend a pony could ever have,
and she's always there to help any pony.
The only trouble is, when she needs help, she finds it hard to accept it.
So while friendship is about giving of ourselves to friends, it's also about accepting what our friends have to offer.
Your faithful student, Twilight Sparkle
How about y'all take a little break? I got some fine apple juice waitin' for ya!
Girls, I can't thank you enough for this help. I was acting a bit stubborn.
A bit?
Okay. A might' stubborn, and I'm awful sorry.
Now, I know the town gave me the Prized Pony award.
But the real award is having you five as my friends.
That applebucking sure made me hungry.
And I've got the perfect treat.
Eeew... Spike, I threw those all away. Where'd you get them?
From the trash.
Just a little nibble? Come on.