Now, what have we learned?
- Lots of control.
- Good.
- Screaming and hollering.
- Yes, and most importantly?
- Passion!
- Right!
So now that you know the elements of a good cheer, let's hear one.
Yay.
You're gonna cheer for me like that? Louder.
- Louder!
- Yay.
LOUDER!
Yay.
Too loud?
And now, phase one of my routine.
Phase two.
Way to go.
Here we go. Phase three. The Sonic Rainboom.
Last one.
Thank you so much for helping me clean up all these books guys.
It was a crazy week of studying.
Rainbow Dash, you rock!
Did my cheering do that?
Sorry about that ladies. That was a truly feeble performance.
Actually, it wasn't all bad. I particularly liked it when you made the clouds spin.
I'm not talking about my performance, I'm talking about yours. That feeble cheering!
What are you two arguing about?
Were we arguing? I'm sorry.
I wish you guys could come to Cloudsdale to see me compete in the Best Young Flyer Competition.
What's that?
It's where all the greatest pegasus flyers get together and show off their different flying styles!
Some are fast!
And some are graceful.
Golly. I'd love to see you strut yer stuff in that competition.
Yeah. I wish you guys could be there. Fluttershy's a great support, but her cheering isn't exactly inspirational.
I'd love to see you make a Sonic Rainboom! It's like, the most coolest thing ever!
Even though I've never actually seen it, but I mean COME ON! It's a Sonic Rainboom! How not cool could it possibly not be?!
What's a Sonic Rainboom?
You really need to get out more.
The Sonic Rainboom is legendary! When a pegasus like Rainbow Dash gets going soo fast...
A sonic boom and a rainbow can happen all at once!
And Rainbow Dash here's the only pony to ever pull it off!
It was a long time ago... I was just a filly.
Yeah, but you're gonna do it again, right?
Are... you kidding? I'm the greatest flyer to ever come out of Cloudsdale! I could do Sonic Rainbooms in my sleep.
If you pull that off, you'll win the crown for sure!
The grand prize is an entire day with the Wonderbolts.
A whole day of flying with my life-long heroes... It'll be a dream come true!
Yay.
I'm gonna go rest up. Don't wanna over prepare myself, y'know. Hehe.
YOU, on the other hand, better keep practicing.
I need a cheering section to match my spectacular performance.
She's practiced that move a hundred times, and she's never even come close to doing it.
I don't know if I can cheer loud enough to help her.
Well, guess we better get this cleaned up... Again.
Go on, go on.
Go on what?
Find a spell that will get us wingless ponies into Cloudsdale. Didn't you see how nervous she was?
Nervous? Have you spit yer bit or somethin'? She was tootin' her own horn louder then the brass section of a marching band!
Oh, puh-lease. I have put on enough fashion shows to recognize stage fright when I see it.
We've got to find a way to be there for her. Now go on!
How am I supposed to find a flight spell in this mess?
A flight spell? One sec.
Page twenty-seven.
How'd you do that?
It landed on my face when Rainbow Dash knocked me into the bookcase.
Here it is! A spell that will allow earth ponies to fly for three days.
It looks really difficult... I'm not sure I can do it.
You've got to try!
Ok... But who's gonna volunteer to be the test subject?
I will! For Rainbow Dash, I will go first.
Here goes.
I think it worked!
You've got to learn to be assertive, Fluttershy. Don't be afraid to speak up.
Well well well. What do we have here?
It's our old friend, Rainbow Crash!
Get kicked outta any flight schools lately?
I didn't get kicked out.
Face it, Rainbow Crash. Flight school had too many rules, and not enough naptimes for you.
Ask her about the Sonic Rainboom.
That's nothing but an old mare's tale. You don't have the skills to try something like that.
Now wait just a minute!
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm trying to be more assertive.
Anyhow... She is going to do a Sonic Rainboom!
No she's not, 'cause there's no such thing!
Then show up at the cloudasium and see for yourself!..
If you're free.
Yeah, I'll be free.
Oh, don't worry. We'll be there!
See you then, Rainbow Crash!
Did you see that? I was so assertive!
Those guys are right. I'll never be able to do it.
But Rainbow Dash. Just because you've failed the Sonic Rainboom a hundred thousand times in practice
doesn't mean you won't be able to do it in front of an entire stadium, full of impatient,
super-critical sportsfan ponies.
What do I do?! Every pony's gonna see me fail! The Wonderbolts will never let a loser like me join.
Princess Celestia will probably banish me to the Everfree Forest!
MY LIFE IS RUINED!!
Rare...
Rare?! The Sonic Rainboom is WAY more than rare!
Rarity?
Rarity! Are you... flying?!
I most certainly am! Aren't my wings smashing?! Twilight made them for me. I just adore them!
Why so shocked? We couldn't leave our favorite flyer without a big cheering section!
We?
I... I can't believe it!
It's incredible!
This is so cool! You guys made it!
- Sure did!
- WAIT!
How'd you do that? Only pegasus ponies can walk on clouds.
Pretty cool, huh?
I found a spell that makes temporary wings, but it was too difficult to do more than once.
So I found an easier spell that lets the rest of us walk on clouds.
And we came to cheer you to victory!
To be honest, I was starting to get just a tiniest, tinyest bit nervous.
But I feel a LOT better now that you guys are here.
Hey, we've got some time before the competition. Why don't Fluttershy and I show you around Cloudsdale?
Here it is: the greatest city in the sky!
Some of the greatest pegasi in history came from Clousdale!
Wait for me!
Those wings are gorgeous!
Why, thank you!
Be careful with those wings Rarity. They're made from gossamer and morning dew, and they're incredibly delicate.
Don't worry Twilight. I'm sure they can't get worn out from too much attention?
Since we're up here, I'd shure like to get a look at where the weather's made.
Great idea! C'mon girls. To the weather factory!
This is where they make the snowflakes. Each one is hoofmade. As you can see, it's a delicate operation.
The snowflakes look even better from up here.
We better move on before Rarity ruins winter and causes a drought.
And here's where they make the rainbows!
Spicyyyyyy!
Yeah, rainbows aren't really known for their flavor.
Where'd you get those amazing wings? I want a pair!
Yeah, I guess I could see that.
Oh hey look, it's Rainbow Crash again!
Yeah! Rainbow... Umm...
Crash!
Rarity! What're you doing talking to these guys?
Oh, they were just admiring my wings Rainbow Dash.
Yeah, you should forget the Sonic Rainboom and just get yourself some wings like these!
C'mon girls. Why don't we go see how clouds are made?
Don't listen to them. You're gonna win that competition for sure!
Are you kidding? I can't DO the Sonic Rainboom,
and just look at these boring, plain old feathered wings. I'm doomed!
Why, these old things? Go ahead everypony. Photos are encouraged.
Rarity. We're supposed to be helping Rainbow Dash relax, remember?
Put your wings away and stop showing off!
How can you ask me to put away perfection?
Rainbow Dash. Are you ok? You don't look so good.
Of course! Why wouldn't I be ok?
Everyone's so in love with Rarity's wings
that they won't even notice when I totally blow it in the Best Young Flyer's Competition.
There's an idea! YOU should enter the competition!
Yeah! I could watch you fly all day long!
There really isn't anypony who uses their wings quite like me. Perhaps I should compete.
WHAT?!
What am I gonna DO?! I'll never win the competition now...
I'm going to be awhile!
Fillies and gentlecolts! Please rise and join me in welcoming our beloved Princess Celestia!
Please welcome our celebrity judges for the Best Young Flyer Competition. The Wonderbolts!
And, let's find out who will take the prize as this year's best young flyer!
Ok contestant number one, you're up.
Ok number two, let's go.
C'mon c'mon, we ain't got all day!
She's talking to you!
Oh I guess that's me!
Ok number four, time to go.
I'm number four, and I need just one more itsy-bitsy minute.
Be a dear and have somepony go ahead of me, hmm?
Look, I don't care who it is, but somepony's gotta go on!
Let's DO THIS!
What am I gonna do?
I loved number seven. Doing fifteen barrel-rolls in a row can't be easy.
My favorite is number ten. She just looked like such a nice pony.
Wonder how come we haven't seen Rainbow Dash or Rarity yet? The competition's almost over.
Number fifteen, let's go!
Rarity... Is ready!
Look ladies. I don't know what to tell you. There's only time for one more performance.
If you both want to compete, you'll just have to go out there together!
Well Rainbow Dash? Shall we?
And now, for our final competitor of the day, contestant number fifteen!!
Uhh... And apparently contestant number four...
Good luck Rainbow Dash. Just do your best.
I hope you don't mind, but I took the liberty of changing our music.
That "rock and roll" doesn't really match my wings.
C'mon Rainbow Dash. You can do this. Just remember the routine. Phase one.
Nice work Rainbow Crash!
Time for phase two.
Look! Phase two is working.
And now for my grand finale.
I will fly right up to the sun and beam my beautiful wings over the whole city of Cloudsdale!
They'll be talking about it for years!
Looks like this is my last chance to turn things around.
Phase three. The Sonic... Rainboom.
Wings, don't fail me now!
Look upon me Equestria, for I Am Rarity!
Oh no! Her wings evaporated into thin air!
Hold on Rarity! I'm coming!
I can't look!
A SONIC RAINBOOM!! SHE DID IT! SHE DID IT!! WOOOOOO!!!!
A SONIC RAINBOOM!! WOOOOOO!!!! YEAH!!!!!
I did it. I did it!
You sure did. Oh thank you Rainbow Dash. You saved my life!
Oh yeah. I did that too.
BEST DAY EVER!
I want to apologize to all of you for getting so carried away with my... beautiful wings. I guess I just lost my head.
- It's ok.
- Don't worry about it kiddo.
- We still love you.
And I'm especially sorry that I was so thoughtless as to jump into the contest at the last minute
after you had worked so hard to win it. Can you ever ever forgive me?
Aw, it's ok. Everything turned out alright, right?
I just wish I could have met the Wonderbolts when they were awake.
OhmygoshohmygoshohmygoshohmygoshohMYGOSH!
So you're the little pony who saved our lives. We really wanted to meet you, and say thanks.
OhmygoshOhmygoshOhmygoshOhmygoshOhmygosh!
Princess.
Hello Twilight Sparkle, and hello to your friends too.
Princess Celestia, I am sorry I ruined the competition. Rainbow Dash here really is the best flyer in Equestria.
I know she is my dear.
That's why for her incredible act of bravery, and her spectacular Sonic Rainboom,
I'm presenting the grand prize for best young flyer to this year's winner, Miss Rainbow Dash!
OhmygoshOhmygoshOhmygoshOhmygoshOhmygoshOHMYGOSHOHMYGOSHOHMYGOSH!
So Twilight Sparkle, did you learn anything about friendship from this experience?
I did Princess, but I think Rarity learned even more than me.
I certainly did. I learned how important it is to keep your hooves on the ground, and be there for your friends.
Excellent. Well done Rarity.
This really is the BEST DAY EVER!
- Uhh, hey Rainbow Crash.
- Dash!
Sorry Rainbow Dash. Uhh, we just wanted to congratulate you on winning the competition.
That Sonic Rainboom was awesome!
Thanks guys.
Uhh, we're really sorry we gave you such a hard time before.
Aww, that's ok. Don't worry about it.
You wanna hang out with us? Maybe you could show us how you did that incredible trick!
Sorry boys.
But I've got plans!