Eyes over here, Spike!
Uh, sorry.
For this to work, it's crucial we keep our concentration totally on the...
Spike! This magic needs our full attention to make it happen. There's no other way!
I can't help it.
Look.
Nevermind her, she's just being Pinkie Pie.
Super-extra Pinkie Pie today.
Twitchy twitcha twitcha twitch.
Pinkie pie? What in the wide-wide-world of Equestria, are you up to?
It's my tail! It's my tail! It's a-twich a-twichin'!
And you know what that means!
Actually, Pinkie, I haven't the slightest idea.
The twichin' means my Pinkie Sense is telling me that stuff's gonna start falling! You should better duck for cover.
Oh, Pinkie, it's not gonna rain. Why there's barely even a cloud in the- ugh!
He just said, "nice catch" in Frog.
Oh, I'm so, so sorry. You okay, Twilight Sparkle?
I just couldn't stand to see the pond getting so over-populated, what with the frogs all hopping into each other and all,
so I decided to fly as many as I can on over to Froggy Bottom Bog.
Of course you did.
Bye-bye!
Twilight? You gotta little somethin' on your face there.
Oh, really? Did your Pinkie Sense tell you that, too?
Nah! I could just see it.
C'mon, Spike, let's continue our practice session where there's a little less, commotion.
Wow! That was amazing! Pinkie Pie predicted that something would fall, and it did!
Oh, come on. She said that something would fall, and a frog just happened to fall at the same time.
A coincidense, nothing else to it.
My tail! My tail! Twitch-a-twitch! Twitch-a-twitch!
Somethin' else is gonna fall!
Pinkie, please. Nothing else is gonna FAAAA...
Oh, no, Twilight fell! Is it... safe to go help her?
It's okay, my tail stopped twitching.
That was amazing!
Please.
Uh, Twilight? Why are you hanging out in a ditch?
Because, Pinkie Pie predicted it!
Honestly, Spike, she did not. Two coincidents in a row like this may be unlikely,
but it's still easier to believe than twitchy tails that predict the future.
Twitchy tail? Pinkie Sense?
Don't worry, it's safe. Prediction already came true.
Oh, wait. Don't tell me you believe in this stuff, too?
I know it doesn't make much sense, but those of us who have been in Ponyville a while,
have learned over time that, if Pinkie's-a-twichin', you better listen.
My ears are flopping! My ears are flopping!
What does that mean?!
I'll start a bath for you.
A bath? This keeps on getting more ridiculous by the minute!
Sooo, basically, it works like this: I get different, little, niggly feelings and they mean different things.
Like when my back is itchy, it means it's my lucky day.
And, when my knee gets pinchy, that means something scary's about to happen.
Is your knee pinchy now?
No, but my shoulder's achy, that means there's an alligator in the tub.
How come your knee didn't get pinchy?! That isn't just scary, it's downright dangerous!
No it's not, silly! This is my pet alligator, Gummy, He's got no teeth. See?
Okay, okay... I get it.
Well, I still don't believe all this... "special power" stuff. It's just a bunch of mumbo-jumbo.
What's not to believe? You do magic, what's the difference?
Huge! For one thing...
...magic is something you study and practice.
It only happens when you decide to do it. It's meant to make something specific that you choose to happen, happen.
But you, uh, it makes no sense at all!
That's so not true, Twilight!
Sometimes it's a bunch of random things happening to my body at random times that supposedly predict the future.
I call 'em "combos".
Combos?
Sure! You know, like, ear flop, then knee twitch, then eye flutter,
that means the sky is about to be graced by a beautiful rainbow!
Yeah, sure.
Combo coming on.
Ear flop, eye flutter, knee twitch!
You said that combo meant beautiful rainbow.
Oh no-no-no-no-no, you're thinking of an ear flop, then knee twitch, eye flutter.
This was an ear flop, then eye flutter, then knee twitch.
That usually means "look out for opening doors". You okay?
I don't believe this.
You don't believe because you don't understand.
Okay, now when you get another twitch, we'll have all kinds of scientific information.
Okey-dokey-lokey!
Any twitches yet?
Nopey-dopey!
Now? Anything?
Wait! Hold on!
Uhh, no.
Are you kidding me?! After a whole day of non-stop twitching, now that I've got you all hooked up, you're not getting a single one?
I don't control it, they just come and go.
That makes no sense!
Sometimes you just have to believe in things, even when you can't figure 'em out.
I will not believe in anything I cannot explain.
Wait, hold on, I'm feeling something...
Oh my gosh, what? What is it?!
It's my tummy! That usually means I'm hungry! Let's eat!
You know what?
Just forget it! I don't need to know if this is real or not, I don't need to understand it. I don't even care!
Okey-dokey-lokey.
Pinkie? Have you seen Twilight?
Twilight? What are ya doing back there?
Did you two plan this?
Plan what?
This is ridiculous. This can't be happening. This makes no sense. I have to figure this out.
Twilight?
Honestly, Spike, don't you know better to sneak up on ponies?
Sorry, but, um, well, isn't that what you're doing?
No! I'm doing scientific research.
I'm observing Pinkie Pie, scientific name: Pinkius Piecus, in its natural habitat.
Pinkius-whoicus?
There's something fishy going on with the whole twitchy prediction thing, and I'm getting to the bottom of it.
So, shh.
Come on, Pinkius Piecus is on the move.
Itchy nose...
That makes no sense.
See, she's hiding like something's about to fall out of the sky,
but a twichy tail means that somethings about to fall from the sky, not an itchy nose.
- This proves perhaps conclusively that...
- Gah!
Spike! Where are you going? I'm trying to teach you the value of scientific...
What's she doing now?
Smelling a flower.
Holy guacamole! I wonder what that means.
Probably that the flower smells good.
Wait. I'm getting something.
Ear flop, eye flutter, knee twitch.
Hold on... You told me that's the combo that says "watch out for opening doors"!
You really, really believe this stuff, don't you?
Here, let me show you there's nothing to be afraid of.
You see?
I promise you there's nothing to fear from that...
Twilight! You came to visit my new apple cellar, how nice.
Twi? You okay? Uh, Twi?
Here, let me help you.
Okay, take this down:
twitchy tail.
Twitchy tail? TWITCHY-TAIL!
Hush, Spike! We can't let Pinkie know we're here, remember?
Something's gonna fall, something's gonna fall! Run for your lives.
Spike honestly, you're overreact...
Hey, Applejack. Whatchya doin'?
Takin' more apples to my new apple cellar. How 'bout you Pinkie? Whatchu doin'?
Oh, letting Twilight secretly follow me all day, without me knowing.
You mean you knew all along?! Why didn't you tell me?
Silly, that would've spoiled the secret!
Tail... still twitching?
All done, clear skies from here on in, as far as I can tell.
Oh no! What does that one mean?
Dunno, never gotten any like it before.
But whatever that shudder's about, it's a doozie.
Something you never expect to happen is gonna happen!
And its gonna happen... At Froggy Bottom Bog!
That's where Fluttershy's headed!
Oh no! Is it about her?
Uh, I'm not sure.
We better go and make sure she's okay.
Calm down everypony. All we know right now is that Pinkie Pie just got a case of the shivers. That's all.
Hey! I thought you didn't believe in this stuff.
I don't. I just want to be there to see the look on Pinkie's face when we find out nothing's wrong.
Okey-dokey!
Cold? Need a jacket or something?
No thanks, I'm fine.
So... What do you think happened to Fluttershy?
I hope nothin'.
I know, but, what do you think happened?
I'm tryin' not to think about it.
Me too. But I'm thinkin' about it, anyway.
Like, what if, she exploded?
Just exploded? For no reason?
- Yeah, like. boom!
- Woah!
I know.
What if... What if she exploded, and then... and then exploded again!?
Can you do that? Can you explode twice?
Of course not.
But, what if, she exploded, and exploded again, and then... ugh!
Will you two stop? She's fine, I'm sure of it.
I hope your right, for Fluttershy's sake.
Look! There's Froggy Bottom Bog!
Fluttershy!
Fluttershy?
Fluttershy! You're okay!
Of course.
What a relief.
I'm so glad everything's alright.
Sorry, I know its not nice to gloat but...
AHA! I told you there was nothing to worry about and I was right.
Pinkie Pie said whatever she was shuddering about was a [couch] doozie,
and the only [cough] doozie here is how right I am.
Twilight?
Pinkie's made a lot of predictions today but [cough] ugh, what is that smell?
But what we've shown here is that there's no point in believing [cough] in anything you can't see for yourself.
W-well t-then s-see what's b-b-behind you, Twilight.
I see it... But I don't believe it!
Is that a hydra!?
Who cares? RUN!
Pinkie! Come on!
I'm so sorry.
- Everypony up that hill!
- He-e-elp!
Coming, Spike! Hang on!
I think we're gonna make it.
But Pinkie's still shuddering!
Oh, lookie there, it stopped.
Oh, there it is again.
He'll be up here in no time! Quick, one at a time, cross!
Do you know any spells for turnimg a hydra into a mouse?
No.
- How about a squirrel?
- No!
- How about...
- No small rodents of any kind!
That's too bad.
A hop, skip, and a... jump!
He's too close. I'll distract him. You two go, now!
What would a brave pony like Rainbow Dash do...?
CHAAARGE!
T-Twilight?
T-Twilight! You have to jump!
I'll never make it!
You'll be fine!
I will not!
It's your only ho-o-ope!
You have to take the leap of faith!
No!
Oh no! Noooo!
I knew you could do it, Twilight!
I don't know how it happened; coincidence, dumb luck, or what,
but you said there'd be a doozie here at Froggy Bottom Bog, and I'd say we just had ourselves one heck of a doozie.
I mean that hydra...
Pinkie?
That wasn't it.
What wasn't what?
What are you talking about Pink?
The hydra wasn't the doozie.
I'm still getting the shudders.
You see? There it is again. Whatever the doozie was at Froggy Bottom Bog, my Pinkie Sense says it still hasn't happened.
But I-WHAT!? The hydra wasn't the doozie?! How could it not be the doozie?! What could be doozier than that?
Dunno, but it just wasn't it.
I give up...
Give what up, Twi?
The fight. I can't fight it anymore.
I don't understand how, why, or what, but Pinkie Sense somehow... makes sense.
I don't see how it does, but it just does.
Just because I don't understand doesn't mean its not true.
Y-y-y-you m-m-mean you b-b-b-believe?
Yup, I guess I do.
That was it. That's the doozie.
What? What is?
You. Believing. I never expected that to happen. That was the doozie, oh and, oh what a doozie of a doozie it was!
Oh, good, Spike, you're here. Take a letter.
With pleasure, Twilight.
Dear Princess Celestia, I'm happy to report that...
Spike, what have I been saying about focus?
I know, but I... Well...
What's wrong Spike, never thought you'd see me with an umbrella hat on?
Not really, no.
Pinkie's tail's a-twitchin'. What else can I do?
I am happy to report that I now realize there are wonderful things in this world you just can't explain,
but that doesn't neccesarilly make them any less true. It just means you have to choose to believe in them.
And sometimes it takes a friend to show you the way.
- Honk!
- Honk...
Always, your faithful student, Twilight Sparkle
There it goes again.
I wonder what's gonna drop outta the sky this time.
You never know.
Twitchy tail?
Holy guacamole!