Let's quiet down please. We have a very important lesson to get to.
Thank you. Today we are going to be talking about cutie marks.
Boring.
You can all see my cutie mark, can't you?
Like all ponies, l wasn't born with a cutie mark. My flank was blank.
She's so precious!
Then one day, when l was about your age, l woke up to find that a cutie mark had appeared.
Look at her hair!
Yes l know, but honestly, that's how everypony was wearing their mane back then.
l had decided to become a teacher, and the flowers symbolized my hope that l could help my future students bloom
if l nurture them with knowledge.
The smiles represented the cheer l hope to bring to my little ponies while they were learning.
Now, can anyone tell me when a pony gets his or her cutie mark?
When she discovers that certain something that makes her special!
That's right, Twist.
A cutie mark appears on a pony's flank when he or she finds that certain something that makes them different from every other pony.
Discovering what makes you unique isn't something that happens overnight,
and no amount of hoping, wishing, or begging, would make a cutie mark appear before its time.
What!
Apple Bloom! Are you passing a note?
What could be so important that it couldn't wait until after class?
It's blank.
Remind you of anypony?
Want some sweets? I've got some peppermint sticks. I made them myself.
They'll make you smi-i-le.
No...
I don't know why we had to sit through a lecture about getting a cutie mark.
I mean, waiting for your cutie mark is sooo last week. You got yours, I just got mine. We all have them already.
I mean, almost all of us have them already.
Don't worry you two, you're still totally invited to my cute-ceanera this weekend.
It's going to be amazing.
It's a party celebrating me and my fantastic cutie mark. How could it not be?
Bump! Bump! Sugar-lump, rump!
Gimme a break.
See you this weekend.
Blank flanks!
It's not fair! It's just not fair!
Don't get your mane in a tangle. You'll get your cutie mark. Every pony gets one eventually.
But I don't want one eventually!
I want one right now! I can't go to Diamond Tiara's cute-ceanera without one, I just can't!
'course you can. Y'know, I was the last pony in my class to get my cutie mark, and I couldn't be prouder of it.
I know my future was to run Sweet Apple Acres, and these bright shiny apples sealed the deal.
Come to think of it, Granny Smith was the last one in her class, too. Huh, same as Big Macintosh.
I really don't see how that's supposed to make me feel better. It probably means that being the last one in your class to get a cutie mark runs in the family.
...runs in the family. Runs in the family!
Runs in the family!
You've got apples for your cutie mark, Granny Smith has an apple pie, Big Macintosh has an apple half,
my unique talent must has som'n to do with apples!
Apples apples apples!
Apples.
Get your delicious nutritious apples here!
Delicious and nutritious, and so many uses!
You can eat 'em, play with 'em...
Hey, watch it!
...create fine art for your home with 'em.
You have to be crazy not to get a bushel of your very own.
She's so creative.
You sir, care t' buy some apples?
No thanks.
- Why not?
- I have plenty at home.
- Are you sure?
- Yes I'm pretty sure I...
You're pretty sure, but you're not absolutely positively completely super-duper sure, are you?
If I buy some apples, will you please leave me alone?
Aaal-right!
You forgot your change!
That's how you sell s'm apples and get a cutie mark!
So, what does my cutie mark look like? A shopp'n bag full of apples? A satisfied customer eating an apple?
Maybe I gotta increase my sales figures first.
YOU TOUCH IT, YOU BUY IT. We take cash or credit.
I'm sorry ma'am.
Ma'am!
Apple Bloom, you can't just...
That'll be four bits.
I didn't put those in my bag.
Likely story. Four bits, lady!
Apple Bloom! I am really really sorry about that. She's new.
Here, take these. No charge.
...and these.
Y'all come back now, y'hear?
What?
Sorry little sis, but your apple-sellin' days are over.
What? But how else am I gonna get my cutie mark?
Home. Now.
Listen sugar-cube, I know it's hard to wait for your very own cutie mark, but, you just can't force it.
Besides, you're not that grown-up just yet. Ain't there other fillies in your class without one?
Well... Twist doesn't have hers yet.
Do you think you'd feel better if you went to the party with her?
Well there you go. Bet you and Twist would have a great time together.
Now run along and find your friend.
You're sure you don't want me to stick around 'till the end of the market?
Hey! Who's been using my racket?
Yeah. I'm sure.
What's up Apple Bloom?
So I was thinkin'... maybe we could go to Diamond Tiara's cute-ceanera together.
I don't have a cutie mark, you don't have a cutie mark.
Well, um...
Isn't my cutie mark swell? I've always loved making my own favorite sweets, but it took me some time to discover that it was my super-special talent.
Pretty sweet, huh?
Yeah, pretty... sweet.
Hey... this doesn't mean we can't go to the cute-ceanera together. You're still gonna come to the party, are you?
- Of course she will.
- It's not like being the only pony there without a cutie mark, would be, like, the most embarassing thing ever.
Looks like some pony's got a dark cloud hanging over her head.
Let me do something about that.
What's the matter, kid?
There's a cute-ceanera this afternoon and everypony in my class will be there and they'll all have their cutie marks and I wanna get my cutie mark
but I'm no good at sellin' apples but I really wanna go to the party but how can I go to the party if I don't have my cutie mark
which my big sister says I'm gonna get eventually but... I WANT IT NOW!
Cutie mark? I can get you a cutie mark like that!
Applejack says these things take time. I have to just wait for it to happen.
Why wait for something to happen when you can make it happen?
But Applejack says th...
Hey, who are you gonna listen to, Applejack, or the pony who was first in her class to get a cutie mark?
I always liked flying an' all, but I was going nowhere in a hurry.
It wasn't until my very first race that I discovered a serious need for speed, and KAZAAM,
this sweet baby appeared as fast as lightning.
That's right, stretch out those legs. Gotta be nice and loose.
The key here is to try as many things as possible as quickly as possible. One of them is bound to lead to your cutie mark.
Are you ready?
I'm ready!
I said: Are! You! Ready!
I'M READY!
Juggling, go!
Hang-gliding, go!
Karate, go!
Kite-flying, go!
Ultrapony Roller Derby, go!
Tried that one... tried that one... tried that one...
Your new outfit is, like, perfect for the party.
I know. It totally shows off my cutie mark.
I love being special.
Can you imagine how embarrassing it must be to be... not special?
I don't even want to, like, think about it.
Tried that one... tried that one...
I'm doomed. Doomed! I'll never find something I'm good at.
You look like you'd be good at eating cupcakes.
Eatin' cupcakes?
Eatin' cupcakes!
I really appreciate all your help Rainbow Dash.
You're a really great coach and I really learned a lot from you and I'm sure I can learn a lot more but...
I've got some cupcakes to eat!
See you at cute-ceanera!
Hold on Pinkie Pie, I'm comin'.
I can't believe I didn't think of this. A cupcake-eating cutie mark, it's sooo obvious.
Now, where are those cupcakes? I'm ready t' chow down!
I don't have any cupcakes.
But you look like you'd be good at helping me make some.
I guess, uh, making-cupcakes cutie mark could work too.
All you have to do is take a cup of flour, add it to the mix
Now just take a little something sweet, not sour, a bit of salt, just a pinch
Baking these treats is such a cinch, add a teaspoon of vanilla
Add a little more, and you count to four, and you never get your fill-a!
Cupcakes – so sweet and tasty
Cupcakes – don't be too hasty
Cupcakes – cupcakes, cupcakes, CUPCAKES!
Hot, hot, hot!
Those look much better than the last batch.
I guess I'm not cut out to be a baker either.
I just have to face it, I'm gonna have a blank flank forever.
What about that?
What about what? Is there something on my flank? Is there, is there, is there?
A cutie mark! It's a... a measuring cup? No. A mixin' bowl? No... Are those cupcakes?
A tower of cupcakes maybe.
Flour. It's flour!
Yay! I guessed it. What game you wanna play next? Please say bingo, please say bingo.
Whoa, what's been going on in here?
We've been making cupcakes, wanna try them?
No thank you... not that they don't look...
delicious.
Twilight, you have to help me.
What's the matter?
Tiara's cute-ceanera's today and everypony in my class will be there and they all have cutie marks and I want to get my cutie mark
but I'm no good at selling apples or hang-gliding or making cupcakes, but I wanna go to the party but how can I go to the party
if I don't have my cutie mark, which Pinkie Pie says I can't just make appear,
but I need it to appear, RIIIGHT NOW!
Aaah I don't follow. How can I help?
You can use your magic to make my cutie mark appear.
Oh no Apple Bloom. A cutie mark is something a pony has to discover for herself.
Please Twilight, just try.
I'm sorry but-
Oh please, please, please please please!
Alright alright!
Oh thank you thank you thank you.
Yes! I knew you could do... it.
I'm sorry sweetie, but I told you-
Try again, try again!
Told you that not even magic can make a cutie mark appear before its time.
It's hopeless, hopeless!
I just won't go to the party, I can't go. Everyone will just laugh at me and make fun of me and call me name.
It will be the worst night of my life.
I'm sure it won't be as bad as all that.
Forget it, there's no way I'm going to that...
... party.
How could I have forgotten the time? How could I have forgotten Pinkie Pie was hosting the party?
How could I have forgotten it was at Sugar Cube corner?
Don't forget your party hat, Forgetty Forgetterson!
I have to get out of here before anypony sees me.
It's my cute-ceanera, I'm supposed to get the first bite at cake.
Okay Apple Bloom, almost there.
Apple Bloom, you made it. After I heard about Twist, I was afraid you wouldn't show up.
I sure am glad you came to your senses about this whole cutie mark thing. These things happen when these things are supposed to happen.
Trying to rush 'em just drives you crazy. I'll let you be, looks like your friends want to talk to you.
Well well well, look who's here.
Nice outfit.
Just something I, uh, pulled together last minute.
It really shows off your cutie mark--oh wait, that's right, you don't have one.
I have a cutie mark.
What? Since when?
Since... Um... Earlier today.
Oh really? Let's see it.
I shouldn't, I couldn't. My cutie mark is so unbelievably amazing, I'm afraid that if I show it off,
everyone will start paying attention to me instead of you. Outshined at your own cute-ceanera,
can you imagine how embarrassing that would be?
Uh, forget it, I didn't really want to see it anyway.
Okay, well, Imma go mingle. Enjoy your party.
Oh no.
Wow, that is an amazing cutie mark.
Nice try, blank flank!
You got a problem with blank flanks?
I said, you got a problem with blank flanks?
The problem is, I mean, she's like, totally not special.
No, it means she's full of potential.
It means she could be great at anything. The possibilities are, like, endless.
She could be a great scientist, or an amazing artist, or a famous writer,
she could even be mayor of Ponyville some day.
...and she's not stuck being stuck-up like you two.
Hey, this is my party, why are you two on her side?
Because...
You don't have cutie marks either? I thought I was the only one.
We thought we were the only two.
I for one think you are three very lucky fillies.
Lucky? How can they be lucky?
They still get to experience the thrill of discovering who they are, and what they're meant to be.
And they got all the time in the world to figure it out, not just an afternoon.
- Wow, Apple Bloom!
- Do you really think you could be mayor?
- I wish I could be a scientist.
Maybe I got my cutie mark too soon.
Hey, what's everypony doing? This is my party, everypony is supposed to be paying attention to me.
Whatever. We still think you're losers, right Diamond Tiara?
Bump, bump, sugar... lump...
Not now, Silver Spoon.
Name's Scootaloo.
Sweetie Belle.
Apple Bloom.
It's all so super!
So I was thinking, now that we're friends... I mean, we are friends, right?
How could we not be? We're totally alike. We don't have cutie marks, Diamond Tiara and Silver Spoon drive us crazy.
Totally crazy.
Now that we're friends, what if the three of us work together to find out who we are and what we're supposed to be?
We could form our own secret society.
I'm liking this idea.
A secret society. Yeah. We need a name for it though.
The Cutie Mark Three?
The Cutastically Fantastics?
How about... The Cutie Mark Crusaders?
It's perfect!
- This is gonna be so great!
- We're gonna be unstoppable!
What do you say we celebrate with some of these delicious cupcakes?
NOT the cupcakes. Trust me.
Let's see if there are any cookies.
Yeah! Come on.
Dearest Princess Celestia, I am happy to report that one of your youngest subjects has learned a valuable lesson about friendship.
Sometimes, the thing you think will cause you to lose friends and feel left out...
...can actually be the thing that helps you make your closest friends and realize how special you are.