Where'd I put that?
Ohh, I thought I already...
Ohh, and I can't forget I've got to--
Oh, how am I ever gonna get this done?
Are you sure I can't help?
I could--
- No!
Maybe just a--
- No thanks!
How about--
- Just stand over there.
But--
- Where you'll be out of the way.
Ribbon, Ribbon!
Where's the ribbon?!
- I got it!
Um...
I-I'll just go and stand over there,
where I'll be...
...out of the way.
My Little Pony, My Little Pony...
Aaaaah...
My Little Pony,
I used to wonder what friendship could be.
until you all shared its magic with me.
Big adventure. Tons of fun.
A beautiful heart, faithful and strong.
Sharing kindness, it's an easy feat,
and magic makes it all complete!
My Little Pony,
Do you know you are my very best friends?
Won't you at least let me help you clean up?
No. You've helped me quite enough.
I'm sorry, sis!
I just thought that if I could help, I might find my special gift
and finally earn my cutie mark.
I understand. It's just that...
I need this time to fill this order without any...
...complications.
Okay, all done.
Now, back to work.
I've lost a lot of time,
and I cannot have any more interruptions.
What now?!
- Oh, sorry. I thought the "open" sign
meant you were open,
but I must have been mistaken.
Fluttershy! Forgive me!
was so wrapped up in my work that I forgot you were
bringing Opalescence back from her grooming!
No worries, Rarity.
I've left her there in the basket.
Oh, she looks great!
I just don't understand how you're able to do it!
I can't get near her without
getting a swipe from her claws.
Ahh! Did you use...
The Stare on her?
Oh, no! I wouldn't! I couldn't!
I-I don't really have any control over when that happens.
I-It just happens.
No, I'm just good with animals.
It's my special gift, you know?
Well, you should have a picture of Opal
as a cutie mark instead of those butterflies.
Maybe I can be good with animals, too!
Or not.
I'm sorry I can't invite you
to stay and chat, Fluttershy.
I've bitten off a bit more
than I can chew with this order.
- But you're not eating anything.
- No, Sweetie,
it's an expression.
It means that I've taken on
more work than I can handle.
I've got twenty of these
special robes to make tonight!
They're due in Trottingham
tomorrow morning.
See? I've lined them in a special gold silk.
It took so long to make, but I think it
adds just the right touch, don't you?
These are lovely,
but twenty by tonight?
How will you get it all done?
Well, I, uh...
Maybe I could... just...
...just stand over here and watch.
- I'll manage.
Well, maybe I should get out of
your mane so you can work.
Hi, Fluttershy!
Hi, Rarity!
Hello, uh, girls...
Hey, Sweetie Belle!
Scootaloo! Apple Bloom!
You ready for tonight?
Yup! Cutie mark planning session is a go!
Tonight is the night we each try
to find our own special talent.
Even if it takes us all night!
I'm ready!
You ready?
Very ready!
Cutie Mark Crusader sleepover at Rarity's!
Yay!
And... look what I made us!
- That's so cool!
What does that patch on your cape mean?
The Cutie Mark Crusaders! Yay!
We're on a crusade, a mission!
To find our cutie marks!
Yup. And look.
I lined them with this special gold silk.
It took sooo long to make,
but I think it adds just the right touch, don't you?
Sweetie Belle!
What have you DONE?
That was the last of the gold silk!
Oh, now I'll have to make more!
Oh, I hope I can make more.
I'm gonna have to work all night!
Which means...
Sorry, girls, I'm afraid the Crusader
sleepover is cancelled.
WHAT?
I just won't have any time to watch you if
I want to get these robes delivered on time.
But--
No buts this time.
I'm sorry, Sweetie Belle;
it's just the way it has to be.
I, ah, I suppose I could
take them for the night.
I couldn't ask you to do that.
Oh, it's no problem at all.
Have you met my sister and her friends?
A problem is all it would be.
Did I have a problem with Opal?
You've seen how well I handle small creatures!
I suppose that's true...
and I do have a lot of work to do...
Come on, it'll be fun.
I assure you, they're quite a handful.
These sweet little angels?
Well...
All right.
Cutie Mark Crusader sleepover
at Fluttershy's cottage!
Yay!
So cute.
W-wait for me!
Oh, won't this be ever so fun?
We can have a nice little tea party,
and braid each other's tails,
and sit quietly and color,
and tell each other fairy tales, and--
Hello, Fluttershy.
Oh! Hello, Twilight.
Where are you off to?
I'm heading to the Everfree Forest, to Zecora's,
to get some of my favorite tea.
Th-the Everfree Forest?
Ah, you'll be careful, won't you?
Of course! How about you?
What are you doing with the girls?
Rarity has a big order to fill tonight, so I volunteered
to take the girls over to my cottage for a sleepover.
Wow. Sounds like everypony
has their hooves full today.
Taking care of those three fillies all by yourself?
You sure you can handle it?
What? These sweet little angels?
They'll be no problem at all.
Wow! Look at this place!
What's that?
Are those tickets?
No problem at all.
Okay, girls, uh, what should we do?
I'm gonna get my mark first!
Girls?
Nuh-uh!
- I am!
Girls, okay, now settle --
- I'm staying up all night!
- Me too!
- Me three!
I-I know you're excited, but--
girls,
oh, oh, careful with the--
oh, ah, girls--
So! What do you wanna do?
Play a game?
We are the Cutie Mark Crusaders!
- And we want to crusade for our cutie marks!
And, and, and, we, um--
Yeah! What they said!
Mmm, I don't know...
How about a nice quiet little tea party?
Or... we could go adventuring
in the Everfree Forest!
Yeah!
Oh, no. The Everfree Forest is much too dangerous.
It's filled with far too many strange creatures.
But you could go with us and
we could catch those creatures.
We could be, umm...
...creature catchers!
YAY! Cutie Mark Crusader creature catchers!
Arrrr... I am a dangerous creature
from the Everfree Forest! Rrrarr!
Halt, dangerous creature from the Everfree Forest.
I am Sweetie Belle, the creature catcher,
and I'm here to catch you!
You can never catch me!
I am far too powerful and dangerous!
You cannot run from me!
Um, oh, maybe that's not such a--
Now, girls...
How about we do some nice colouring? Dhh--
Come back, dangerous creature,
so I can catch you!
Never!
Careful... you don't...
...break anything.
Sorry, Fluttershy.
Yeah, sorry.
I guess we aren't creature catchers.
Oh, girls, it's okay. I--
I know! We could be
Cutie Mark Crusader carpenters!
C-carpenters?
Hammer!
- Hammer.
- Hammer!
Hammer!
Hammer.
Um ... that doesn't look like a table.
We were making a table?
Somepony needs to put
this thing out of its misery.
We are definitely not Cutie Mark Carpenters.
Who wants a picture of a hammer
on their flank anyway?
Well, now that we've gotten
that out of the way,
how about a game?
A game?
It's called "Shhh!".
What's that?
Well, it's a game about who
can be quiet the longest.
Sound fun?
I'm the world champ, you know.
I bet you can't beat me!
I lose! - Me too!
- Me three!
Okay, now what can we do?
Oooh! How about Cutie Mark Crusader coal miners?
YEAH!
NO!
I mean, it's time for bed,
don't you think?
Aren't you excited to get all toasty and warm
in your snuggly-wuggly widdle beds?
Snuggly-wuggly?
But we have more crusading to do!
We've got plans!
And capes!
Um, okay, um. Maybe the crusading
can wait until morning?
When it's light?
And not so... dark?
How are we gonna find
our special talent in our sleep?
Maybe you'll have a lovely little dream
about your special talent.
But we're not even tired!
How about I sing you a lullaby?
Mm-hmm, yeah!
Hush now, quiet now.
It's time to lay your sleepy head.
It's time to go to bed.
I know this one!
Oh, how wonderful!
Why don't you sing it with me?
Hush now! Quiet now!
It's time to lay your sleepy head!
Said hush now! Quiet now!
It's time to go to bed!
- Okay, Sweetie, that was...
- Driftin' (driftin') off to sleep!
The exciting day behind you!
Driftin' (driftin') off to sleep!
Let the joy of dreamland find you!
Thank you, Sweetie, um...
- Hush now! Quiet now!
Lay your sleepy head!
Said hush now! Quiet now!
This's time to go to bed!
What is that?
Girls!
Fluttershy, your chickens are on the loose!
I wonder what could
have caused that...
Don't worry, Fluttershy,
the Cutie Mark Crusaders will handle this!
Cutie Mark Crusader chicken herders!
Yay!
No, I don't think that's a-- ah, come back!
Please!
Come on, girls, the chickens are fine--
oh, girls, um...
GIRLS!
Come on.
In you go.
There's some good chickens.
Okay, you three. Isn't it about
time you got into bed?
- BUT--
Please?
So, no more crusading for tonight,
all right?
Yes, Fluttershy!
- We promise, Fluttershy!
- Good night, Fluttershy!
Okay, good night.
Okay, so what kind of
crusading do we do next?
- There's not much we
can do from this room...
unless we become Cutie Mark
Crusader cottage cleaners.
- N-no, thanks.
Well, we have to think of something.
We can't just waste this opportunity
to find out what our special talents are.
Hey, girls!
Look!
Some of the chickens may have escaped!
Into the forest!
Cutie Mark Crusaders chicken rescuers are go!
It really wasn't THAT hard...
I mean, all I needed to do was
just show them who's in charge.
Nothing's gonna get past Fluttershy!
Good with animals,
good with kids.
Wait up!
Mmm, peace and quiet.
Too quiet.
Girls?
Elizabeak! She's missing!
GIRLS?
Oh, no!
They must have gone looking for
my missing chicken!
Which means...
they must have gone into...
The Everfree Forest!
Those girls have really done it this time!
They've really bitten off
more than they can chew!
Oh, just like me!
I never should have offered to watch them.
Here, chick-chick-chick-chick-chick!
What are you doing?
Calling for the chicken!
That is not how you call a chicken.
Oh, and you know how to call a chicken?
I know that's not the way.
Then show me.
I don't have to show you!
You're just chicken!
Am not!
Oh, wait, now I know
how to call a chicken!
Scootaloo!
Scoot-scootalooooo!
That's so funny I forgot to laugh.
You also forgot how
to call a chicken.
Why, you...
Come on, guys, we're not gonna find
the chicken or our cutie marks by arguing.
Maybe that's our special talent. Arguing!
Is not!
Is too!
- Is not!
- Is too!
Anything yet?
Nope.
- Darn.
Heeeere, chick-chick-chick-chick!
Girls?
Oh! Get a hold of yourself, Fluttershy.
Just put one hoof in front of the other.
Ahh! What was that?
Twilight?
I-is that you?
Oh, Twilight, it is you.
Thank goodness you're here.
I need your help. The girls are out here
somewhere, and I'm afraid that they're--
Oh! What's happened to you?
Oh, no! If you've been
turned to stone, it must mean--
Oh! oh, no, the girls!
Don't move;
I'll be back for you.
GIRLS!
- It's not!
- It's too!
Girls! Our special talent is not arguing.
Besides, what would the cutie mark of somepony
whose talent is arguing even look like?
Girls?
Girls?!
- Fluttershy?
Girls? Thank goodness I found you!
- Fluttershy, what--
- Girls, we have to leave the forest at once!
- But... we haven't found the chicken yet!
- There's no time for that.
There's a cockatrice on the loose!
A cocka what now?
A cockatrice!
It's a frightening creature with
the head of a chicken and the body of a snake.
Now, come on!
The head of a chicken
and the body of a snake?
That doesn't sound scary,
that sounds silly!
Well, if I ever saw one of them cockathingies
face-to-face, I'd laugh at how silly it was.
NO! Never look one in the eye.
If you look a cockatrice in the eye--
- The chicken!
Girls! Wait!
Here, chick-chick-chick-chick-chick!
There it is!
Two chickens?
I thought only one escaped!
Grab them both!
See? Now we have to --
Girls.
Please.
Girls-- now listen to me.
I-- please!
Girls!
GIRLS! Behind me, NOW!
YOU!
Just who do you think you are,
going around turning others into stone?
You should be ashamed of yourself.
I have a mind to find your mother and
tell her what you've been up to, young man.
Now you go over there, and turn Elizabeak
and my friend Twilight back to normal,
and don't ever let me catch you doing this again.
Do you understand me?
Are you girls all right? I was so worried!
Yeah, fine!
Thanks to that stare of yours.
You're like the queen of stares. You're the--
Stare Master!
We're sorry we snuck out
of the house and into the forest.
Yeah. We'll listen to you
from now on.
We promise.
Oh, you DO, do you?
Well, you better, or I'll give you...
...The Stare.
What...
What happened?
And that's when it brought you back from stone.
This is gonna make quite
a letter to the princess.
I was wrong about you.
You certainly do know
how to handle those girls.
Oh, I wouldn't go that far.
Hmm? How so?
I assumed that I'd be just as
good with kids as I am with animals.
Boy, was I wrong.
I really learned the hard way not to
bite off more than I could chew.
You and Rarity both.
Good morning, Rarity.
Did you finish all those capes?
Just delivered them.
I have to admit,
if you hadn't come along,
I might not have.
Thanks again.
Won't you stay for some tea?
I really must get back to the shop and clean up.
Girls! Get your things.
Time to go.
Girls!
Time to--
Your things!
Girls!
It's time to--
GIRLS!
Allow me.
Girls?
Yes, Fluttershy.
- You called?
Go and get your things.
Rarity is here to see you home.
Of course, Fluttershy, right away!
Ah, huh, ah, how did you... how did you do that?
I guess I'm just as good
with kids as I am with animals.
Thank you, Fluttershy! Bye! Thank you Stare Master!
Ah, uh, speaking of which,
I could use your help with Opal.
Of course. How about later today?
How about now?