Hoof-biting action overload! She was like a stunt superstar, flying higher and higher,
and then Rainbow Dash swooped down, swoosh, and right before she hit the ground, shoom, she pulled up, rrrmmm!
And then she looped around and around like fwoom fwoom fwoom fwoom fwoom fwoom fwoom.
Rainbow Dash!
Pinkie Pie? Not again.
Not now, Pinkie Pie.
But, but Rainbow Dash...
I'm in the middle of something.
- But...
- I said not now...
I was gonna tell you to look out for that mountain.
Hi, I'm looking for Rainbow Dash. Have you seen her?
Hi there, have you seen Rainbow Dash? Okay, thanks anyway.
Twilight, have you seen Rainbow Dash anywhere?
Isn't she right up there?
Rainbow Dash!
That was close.
Hi!
Hi again.
I need a favor, Rainbow Dash.
Forget it.
I totally promise it would be totally fun.
Okay...
Over to the right. No no, a little to the left. Oh wait, back to the right.
Now a little leftish while staying rightly.
Stop.
Maybe a few inches to the south. Now a couple centimeters north.
Okay. One more smidgimeter to the...
Pinkie Pie!
I mean, perfect. Now wait for my signal.
Oh Rainbow Dash, we startled Spike into getting the hiccups.
Good one, Pinkie [hiccup] Pie. [hiccup] You're always pulling a fast one [hiccup] on me.
Oh no, you're not hurt are you?
Ne [hiccup] eh, don't be [hiccup] silly, dragons are [hiccup] fire-proof.
Oh, okay, good.
I wish the same thing [hiccup] were true with scrolls.
Have you ever seen anything more hilarious?
I can think of one thing.
I didn't take you for a prankster, Pinkie Pie.
Are you [hiccup] kidding? [hiccup] I love to pull pranks. It's all [hiccup] in good fun, and Pinkie Pie lo [hiccup] oves to have [hiccup] fun! [hiccup]
You know Pinkie Pie, you're not as annoying as I thought.
You wanna hang out?
That'd be [hiccup]
I'd really [hiccup] When do [hiccup]
I mean [hiccup] Why would you [hiccup]
A simple nod would do.
Is she even home?
I don't know, but I think she called.
There she is.
Land sakes!
Is someone over there? Who're we gonna squirt? Who're we gonna squirt?
Fluttershy.
WHAT?
Nonononononono, we can't prank Fluttershy.
I mean, she's so sensitive, it'll hurt her feelings, even our most harmless prank.
Yeah, you're right.
We need another victim who's made of tougher stuff. So, who's it gonna be?
I've got someone in mind.
The toughest around.
Awesome. Who? Who? Do I know them?
Oh, yes.
You're very close.
Good one, Pinkie Pie.
Rise and shine Rainbow Dash, it's a brand new day and got a lot of pranking to...
Mornin', Pink. Gilda, this is my gal pal, Pinkie Pie.
Hey. What's up.
Pinkie, this is my griffon friend, Gilda.
What's a griffon?
She's half-eagle, half-lion.
And all awesome. Raa.
Yeah, that's right.
Gilda's my best friend from my days at Junior Speedster flight camp.
Hey, remember the chant?
Chyeah, they made us recite it every morning, I'll never get that lame thing out of my head.
Sooo...
Only for you, Dash.
Junior Speedsters are our lives
Sky-bound soars and daring dives
Junior Speedsters it's our quest
To some day be the very best
Oh that was awesome, and you've given me a great idea for a prank. Gilda, you game?
Well, I groove on a good prank as much as the next griffon,
but Dash, you promised me we'd get a flying session in this morning.
Yeah, uh, well, Pinkie Pie, you don't mind, do you?
Gilda just got here. We'll catch up with you later.
Sure, no problem. Have fun you guys, so I'll... just catch up with you...
...later.
Wow, that was sweet. Just like old times.
Yeah, only faster. So now what?
Hey there.
It's later. And I caught up.
Pinkie Pie, you are so random.
Hey Dash, think you got enough gas left to beat me to that cloud?
A race? You are so on.
One, two, three, go.
I win.
As if. I won, dude.
- No way.
- Yes way.
- Come on, I was way ahead of you.
- I don't think so.
- Please, dream on.
- Remember back in camp? I...
- There is no way you beat me.
- Whatever.
Wow guys, that was really cool, but I think Rainbow Dash beat you by a teeny weeny itty bitty hair,
or a teeny weeny itty bitty feather.
See? Good thing Pinkie Pie's here to keep you honest, G.
OK, Dash. Last one to that cloud up there is a gnarly dragon egg.
Go!
I think the high altitude is making you dizzy.
Wait, guys...
Wow, you guys almost got away from me that time.
So, Dash, got any new moves in your tricktionary, or are you 100% old school?
New moves? Heh, sit back G, this is gonna take a while.
Hey Pinkie, c'mere.
Yeah?
Don't you know how to take get lost for an answer?
Dash doesn't need to hang with a dweeb like you now that I'm around.
You're dorkin' up the skies, Stinkie Pie, so make like a bee and BUZZ OFF.
Try matching that.
Hey, where's Pinkie Pie and her crazy contraption?
She left. Something about being busy as a bee.
So Pinkie Pie, are you sure that this friend of Rainbow Dash is really so mean?
Yeah, she keeps stealing Rainbow Dash away, she pops my balloons, and she told me to buzz off.
I've never met a griffon this mean. Well actually I've never met a griffon at all.
But I bet if I had, she wouldn't have been as mean and grumpy as Gilda.
You know what I think, Pinkie Pie?
Well, I think... you're jealous.
Jealous?
Green with envy. Well, in your case, pink with envy.
Well, yes. Jealous. Listen Pinkie, I don't want to upset you, but just because Rainbow Dash has another friend doesn't make Gilda a grump.
I mean, perhaps it's you, Pinkie, who needs to improve her attitude.
Improve my attitude? But I... D... B.. Th... Gilda's a... D... Are you seri...
Maybe Twilight is right. Maybe Gilda isn't a big meanie grumpy mean-meanie-pants.
Maybe I'm just a big jealous judgmental jealous-jealousy-pants.
That was sweet.
I gotta take care of a few weather jobs around here. Shouldn't take long. Just, uh, hang out in town and I'll come find you.
That's cool, I guess. I'm gonna go chow down.
Later.
A rattler, a rattler!
Run for the hills! Everybody forsake yourselves!
This stuff ain't fresh, dude.
Poor Granny Smith, she didn't know it was a joke. How mean.
No no, I can't misjudge her. It was kind of a funny prank, I guess.
I did misjudge her. She's not only a meanie mean-pants, she's also a thief.
Nonononono, she might give it back. It's just a joke.
Alright little ones, this way, this way. Mama duck is free and clear.
Please excuse me.
I'm walkin' here.
-  I'm sorry. A-a-I was just trying to...
- "I'm sorry, I'm sorry"
Why don't you just watch where you're going, stupid?
B-b-b-but I... I...
Please, all these lame ponies are driving me buggy. I gotta bail.
She's a grump, and a thief, and a bully. The meanest kind of mean meanie-pants there is.
I can take it, but no one treats Fluttershy like that. No one.
This calls for extreme measures, Pinkie Pie style.
Welcome, welcome. Welcome.
Who's this Gilda I've heard nothing about?
I hear she's an old friend of Rainbow Dash. A griffon, so rare.
You've met Gilda, right? What's she like?
Well, I'll tell you later, Twilight.
Welcome. Welcome.
Pinkie Pie, about this party for Gilda. Do you really think it's a good idea? I mean...
Don't worry your pretty little head about mean old Gilda, your auntie Pinkie Pie has got it all taken care of.
I'm a year older than you.
Gilda! I'm so honored to throw you one of my signature Pinkie Pie parties,
and I really truly sincerely hope you feel welcome here amongst all us pony folk.
Oh, Pinkie Pie, the old hoof-shake buzzer. You are a scream.
Yeah, uh, good one, Pinkie Pie.
Come on G, I'll introduce you to some of my other friends.
Right behind you Dash. I know what you're up to.
Great.
I know what you're planning.
Well I hope so. This wasn't supposed to be a surprised party.
I mean, I've got my eye on you.
And I got my eye on you.
Everyone, I'd like you all to meet Gilda, a long-time dear friend of Rainbow Dash.
Let's honor her and welcome her to Ponyville.
Please help yourself.
Vanilla lemon drops. Don't mind if I do.
HOT!
G, the punch.
Well whaddya know, pepper in the vanilla lemon drops, and the punch served in a dribble glass.
Priceless. Priceless.
Yeah, hilarious.
Hey G, look, presents.
Spittin' snakes. Heh, somepony pulled there prank on me last month.
I bet I know who that was.
You do?
Cake time everypony.
Hey, can I blow out the candles?
Why don't we let Gilda blow out the candles, Spike. She is the guest of honor after all.
Exactly.
Re-lighting birthday candles, I love that prank. What a classic.
Now, I wonder who could've done that.
Yeah, I wonder.
Wwho cares. This cake is amazing.
Spike!
What? It was great, try some.
Hey G, you're not upset about some silly candles, are you?
No way Dash, like I said, I'm down with a good prank.
Come on then, let's have some cake.
Hey, I'm watching you. Like a hawk.
Why? Can't you watch me like a griffon?
Hey y'all, it's pin the tail on the pony. Let's play.
Oh, my favorite game. Can I go first? Can I have the purple tail?
Well I am the guest of honor, I'll have the purple tail.
Yeah, Gilda should definitely go first. Let's get you blindfolded.
Hey what are you doing?
We're spinning you around and around and then you pin the tail on the pony.
Now just walk straight ahead and pin the tail.
"Now just walk straight ahead and pin the tail".
Heh, yeah right, this is another prank isn't it. I'm going this way.
Wait. The poster is this...
Gilda? You pinned the tail on the wrong end.
This is your idea of a good time? I've never met a lamer bunch of dweebs in all my life.
And Pinkie Pie, you, you are queen lame-o with your weak little party pranks,
do you really think you can make me lose my cool? Well, Dash and I have ten times as much cool as the rest of you put together.
Come on Dash, we're bailing on this pathetic scene.
Come on Rainbow Dash. I said, we're leaving.
You know Gilda, I was the one who set up all those weak pranks at this party.
What?
So I guess I'm queen lame-o.
Come on, Dash, you're joshing me.
They weren't all meant for you specifically, it was just some luck that you set them all off.
I shoulda known, that dribble cup had Rainbow Dash written all over it.
No way. It was Pinkie Pie, she set up this party to trip me up, to make a fool of me.
Me? I threw this party to improve your attitude. I thought a good party might turn that frown upside down.
And you sure didn't need any help making a fool of yourself.
You know, this is not how I thought my old friend would treat my new friends.
If being cool is all you care about, maybe you should go find some new cool friend someplace else.
Yeah? Well you, you, you are such an, a flip-flop: cool one minute and lame the next.
When you decide not to be lame anymore, gimme a call.
Not cool.
Wow, talk about a party pooper.
- Wow, what was that about?
- Awkward.
I'm sorry everypony, for bringing Gilda here. I didn't know how rude she was.
And Pinkie Pie, I'm really sorry she ruined that awesome party you put on for her.
Hey, if you want to hang out with party poopers, that's your business.
I'd rather hang out with you. No hard feelings?
No hard feelings.
Hey Pinkie, sorry I accused you of misjudging Gilda. Looks likes I'm the one who misjudged you.
It's okay Twilight, even you can't be a super smart smarty smart-pants all the time.
Come on everypony, there's still a whole lotta partying to fit in.
Dearest Princess Celestia, today I learned that it's hard to accept
when somepony you like wants to spend time with somepony who's not so nice.
Though it's impossible to control who your friends hang out with, it is possible to control you own behavior.
Just continue to be a good friend.
In the end the difference between a false friend and one who's true will surely come to light.
Your faithful student, Twilight Sparkle.
Dear Twilight Sparkle, my most faithful student.
Wrong ink.