Where are you takin' us?
We're almost there, youngin's.
I've never been here before.
- Oh. Sorry.
- Are we there yet?
There? Where? What? I don't even know what we're doing.
Here we are.
What are we lookin' at?
I have no idea.
What is that thing?
Cutie Mark Crusaders, welcome to your new clubhouse.
Well, don't thank me all at once. This was my clubhouse when I was your age.
Sure it hasn't been used in a while, but it's empty and on a secluded, private part of the farm.
And it's all yours. It just needs a little, uh... TLC.
TLC as in Tender Loving Care or Totally Lost Cause?
Applejack! We're supposed to turn this into our new clubhouse?
Well, maybe y'all will get your cutie marks when you discover your talent for...
House cleanin'?
Not so fast!
Hi, Scootaloo! Back already? You're amazin' on that scooter.
Thanks! Wow, Apple Bloom. You did all of this?
Yep! I've fixed the broken shutters, sanded off the splinters, rebuilt the roof, painted...
That's so cool. What's Sweetie Belle up to?
We are the Cutie Mark Crusaders...
...never stop the journey...
There you are, Sweetie Belle! See? I told you we could find her by following her totally awesome voice.
What's that sweet tune you're singing?
I was just working on our new Cutie Mark Crusaders theme song.
Cool!
Teach us?
Well, I've only come up with one part... but okay!
They all say that you will get your mark
When the time is really right
And you know just what you're supposed to do
And your talent comes to light!
Well, uh... I'll be, Cutie Mark Crusaders. You've done one fine job with this place.
So, what's next?
Well, now that we have a real life clubhouse...
And a map of Ponyville.
And a Cutie Mark Crusaders theme song.
Theme song?
We're gonna go out in the world and discover our talents.
- A new adventure!
- And earn our cutie marks.
We'll leave no stone unturned!
No mountain unclimbed!
No meal uncooked!
No song unlearned!
Well okay then! Sounds like you have a plan.
I gotta, uh... Leave no apple unpicked! See y'all later!
Are we ready to get our cutie marks, ponies?
Ready!
- I had nothing to do with this.
- What is going on here?
Well, we sure aren't gettin' our cutie marks for bein' librarians.
I should think not.
What?
Girls, I think you're going about this the wrong way.
Instead of trying to do things in areas you're not familiar with, why not try doing things in areas that you already like?
And I have the perfect place to start.
- "Showcase your talents...
- for all to see...
Perform in the Ponyville school talent show."
There'll be all sorts of awards. Best dramatic performance, best comedy act, best magic act...
Surely you can find your talent.
This would be the perfect place to discover our talents.
- Jugglin'!
- Acting!
- Magic tricks!
- Square dancin'!
- Tightrope walking!
- Tiger taming!
My little ponies! You're missing the point.
Think about the things you already enjoy doing. Think about what you're already good at.
Sure! We can do that.
Yeah! Sure we can.
Well, whatever we do, we'll do it as...
The Cutie Mark Crusaders!
Sweetie Belle! I told you not to touch my things. Come back with my supplies!
We're just borrowing them for the talent show. Don't worry, sis. I promise we'll bring them back.
Thanks, Mr. Breezy. We'll return the fan to you real soon.
What do we need this fan for?
Trust me on this one.
Okay, so that's six wooden planks, four-by-eight plywood, a box of nails, four cans of paint and four brushes.
Anything else?
Yeah. Instructions on how to use six wooden planks, four-by-eight plywood, a box of nails, four cans of paint and four brushes.
"Ghost, Goblins and Ghoulish Figures"? Good heavens, girls. What do you need a book like this for?
You'll see. Thanks, Twilight. We'll give it back as soon as we're done with it.
What do you think they're up to?
I have no idea and I don't know if I should be excited or scared to find out.
I'm glad we're doin' this as a team.
Me too.
Um... so what are we doing again?
A super awesome dramatic song for the talent show, of course.
Right! With super-cool scenery. And amazing costumes!
And mind-blowin' dance moves.
This is gonna be soo amazing!
Sweetie Belle, I think you should be the singer.
What? No way I'm singing in front of a crowd. Twilight said to do something we like to do,
and I'd like to be like my big sister, and she's a designer.
Fine then. You can do the costumes and the scenery.
And Scootaloo, you're great in maneuvers on your scooter. So you should do the choreography.
Y'know, all those dance moves.
Nah. I'd rather sing a wicked rock ballad.
Why don't you come up with the dance routine, Apple Bloom?
I'm not much of a dancer... but I do like Kung-fu. That's kinda like dancin'.
Then it's settled! Let's get started.
One... two... three...
Ow, Apple Bloom! What are you doing?
I feel like I have four left feet. I can't even spin right.
Don't be silly. You just gotta keep your head forward until very the last minute, like this.
See? Easy-peasy. You just gotta practice a bunch, that's all.
That does look easy. Thanks.
Okay. Let's try this again.
I'm okay!
- Keep practicing!
- Will do.
We fight the fight, walk the walk. Talk the talk, eat the... uh... food like a celery stalk?
I'll never come up with anything!
Never, never, never!
Come back! Come back!
Dumb fabric.
Hey Scoot! How's the song going?
Oh my! Sounds serious.
I'm just no good at lyrics. Coming up with words is, like... really hard.
Oh, it can't be that bad.
"With our cutie marks we'll rock Equestria. We use our stomachs to... digestia"?
Well... These are... um... good, but...
How about after "We fight the fight"...
There is nothing that we fear
We'll have to figure out what we'll do next
Till our cutie marks are here
Wow! That's so awesome! Did you just come up with that now?
Yeah... kind of.
Thanks, I'm totally using that.
Oh no!
One, two, three, four, FIVE?!
How's the spin coming along?
I think I gotta just stick to punches and kicks.
You know, ponies only have four legs.
I'll never be a designer like my sister Rarity.
Hey, it's no big deal. Why don't you use the dress form?
It'll help you with your patterns and help you put all the pieces in the right places.
Oh, is that what that's for?
Maybe you should also clean your paintbrush between each color.aybe you should also clean your paintbrush between each color.
Oh, I was wondering why all the colors looked like mud.
You're not using power tools, are you?
The talent show is just around the corner. I wonder how the fillies are doin'.
- Sorry, Scootaloo.
- That's okay.
- Oh, my bad, Sweetie Belle.
Let's sing the chorus again!
Well, gosh. Sure wasn't expectin' that.
I think that sounded pretty good.
Me too. You think we're ready?
Ready as we'll ever be.
Hey! Did you see us practicing?
Uh... Yeah.
Well? How'd we do? How'd we do?
Speechless! See, girls? I told you that's what we're gonna do. We're gonna leave them speechless.
"Speechless" is right.
..and on the count of three this rabbit will disappear and something tasty will reappear in its place.
A one, a two and a three!
Hey! Where are they?
Snails, where are the...
carrots.
Snails!
Uh, how about a round of applause for the S&S magic act?
Now for our next act we have Sunny Days and Peachy Pie reciting their favorite poem... on rollerskates!
Break a leg!
Sweetie Belle! What a thing to say!
No, no, no. You see, in the theater it's considered bad luck to say "good luck".
So you say "break a leg" instead.
My little ponies! How are you doing?
Nervous...
Don't worry. You're gonna be amazing. Remember, just stick to what you know best.
I can't wait to hear you sing, Sweetie Belle.
Why does everypony always think I'm gonna sing?
Actually, Twilight Sparkle, I'm the main singer tonight.
And I'm the main dancer.
- And I'm in charge of...
- Costumes?
And sets and props. How'd you know?
Really, girls? Are you sure...
Cutie Mark Crusaders, you're on next. Break a leg.
Break a le...
Good luck!
Look, here are three little ponies
Ready to sing for this crowd
Listen up, 'cause here's our story
I'm gonna sing it... very loud!
When you're a younger pony
And your flank is very bare
Feels like the sun will never come
When your cutie mark's not there
So the three of us fight the fight
There is nothing that we fear
We'll have to figure out what we'll do next
Till our cutie marks are here
We are the Cutie Mark Crusaders
On a quest to find out who we are
And we will never stop the journey
Not until we have our cutie marks
They all say that you'll get your mark
When the time is really right
And you know just what you're supposed to do
And your talent comes to light
But it's not as easy as it sounds
And that waiting's hard to do
So we test our talents everywhere
Until our face is blue
We are the Cutie Mark Crusaders
On a quest to find out who we are
And we will never stop the journey
Not until we have our cutie marks
We are the Cutie Mark Crusaders
On a quest to find out who we are
And we will never stop the journey
Not until we have our cutie marks!
Wow. That did not go as well as I expected.
I can't believe they're laughin' at us.
Was it that bad?
Back on stage, girls. It's time for the awards.
Back on stage? No.
They'll just laugh some more.
Yeah, what's the point?
Now girls, let's be good sports. You made a great effort. You should be proud. Now come on!
Let's hear it for all our talented fillies and colts.
Our first award goes to... Snips and Snails for best magic act.
Mine's at least shinier.
Well, mine's bigger.
Oh yeah, well... Well, mine is, um... heavier?
The next award goes to... Sunny Days and Peachy Pie for best dramatic performance.
And finally, the last award of the night goes to...
The Cutie Mark Crusaders!
What?
For best comedy act.
Can you believe it? We won!
I knew our act was awesome.
You know what would be the best? If we won and we got our cutie marks.
Congratulations, ponies! Job well done.
Thanks, Twilight.
Hey, you don't sound too excited.
We worked really hard and won a prize but we still don't have our cutie marks.
Which is the prize we really wanted.
Oh, girls...
But we think we know why.
Yes. We know why.
Oh? Tell me. I'd love to make a special report to the Princess.
Well, maybe we were trying too hard?
Yes? And...
And instead of forcing ourselves to do something that's not meant for us...
Yes? Yes?
We each should be embracing our true talent!
And that is...?
Comedy!
Apple Bloom! You did it!
Did you see our award? Weren't we funny?
One day... One day...