I want to start our field trip here,
in the world famous Canterlot Sculpture Garden.
That one over there
represents friendship.
All right, my little ponies!
This one represents victory.
How cool would it be to have
*that* for a cutie mark!
Cool!
If you were actually
victoryful at somethin'.
That's not a word!
What are you? A dictionary?
Girls!
Now this is a really interesting statue.
What do you notice about it?
It's got an eagle claw!
-And a lion paw!
-And a snake tail!
This creature is called a draconequus.
He is the head of a pony and a body
made up of all sorts of things.
What do you suppose that represents?
-Confusion!
-Evil!
-Chaos!
It's not chaos, you dodo!
Don't call me things
I don't know the meaning of!
And it is too chaos!
Is not!
You're both wrong!
Actually, in a way you're all right.
This statue represents discord...
...which means a lack of
harmony between ponies.
In fact, you three have
demonstrated discord so well...
...that you're each going to
write me an essay explaining it.
Now let's go. And I don't
want any more fighting.
-It's confusion!
-Evil!
-Chaos!
Come back here, you!
Gotcha!
Eeew! What is this?
Cotton candy?
Wait a second! It's not supposed
to rain until tomorrow!
You can't just...!
You did.
Hey! I didn't tell you to go anywhere!
Rainbow Dash! What's
going on with that rain?
I mean... chocolate milk?
I mean... chocolate milk rain?!
There's crazy weather
all over Equestria!
Cloudsdale's getting soaked
by a major cola storm right now.
But don't worry. I'm not leaving you,
till I get control of Ponyville.
Why would you wanna stop *this*?
I heard about your troubles, Applejack,
and I came to see if there's anything I could do.
Without getting wet. Or dirty.
Or out from under my umbrella.
Fluttershy! Do somethin'!
Now Angel, you really shouldn't...
No! It's not possible!
I must be seeing things!
Don't worry, everyone! I've learned
a new spell that'll fix everything.
My fail-safe spell...
...failed! What do we do?
Uh... Give up?
Spike. Twilight will come up with something.
Time for Plan B.
Rainbow! Can you corral all those
clouds in one corner of the sky?
Applejack! I need you to bring those
high strong storm clouds down to earth.
Hey! What happened?
Oh dear! I hope that none
of the animals see these...
...delicious chocolate-filled
cotton candy clouds.
I'd hate to have to share them.
You and me both, sister!
Hey!
And when y'all are done that, feel free
to have some popcorn for dessert.
You see, Spike? You
should never give up.
There's nothing we can't
overcome if we all work together.
Come on, girls! Princess Celestia wants
to see us all in Canterlot immediately!
Princess Celestia! We came
as fast as we could.
Thank you, Twilight. Thank you all.
Is this about the weather?
And the animals' weird behavior?
What's happening out there? Why
isn't my magic working? Is there...?
Follow me.
I've called you here
for a matter of great importance.
It seems an old foe of mine...
...someone I thought I had
defeated long ago, has returned.
His name is Discord.
Discord is the mischievous
spirit of disharmony.
Before my sister and I
stood up to him...
...he ruled Equestria in an eternal state
of unrest and unhappiness.
Luna and I saw how miserable
life was for earth ponies...
...pegasi and unicorns alike.
So after discovering
the Elements of Harmony...
...we combined our powers
and rose up against him...
...turning him to stone.
Alright, Princess!
I thought the spell we cast would
keep him contained forever...
...but since Luna and I are
no longer connected to the Elements...
...the spell has been broken.
No longer connected?
This is Canterlot tower, where
the Elements are kept inside...
...since all of you recovered them.
I need you to wield the Elements of Harmony
once again and stop Discord...
...before he thrusts
all of Equestria into eternal chaos.
But why us? Why don't you...?
Hey, look! We're famous!
You six showed the full
potential of the Elements...
...by harnessing the magic of your
friendship to beat a mighty foe.
Although Luna and I
once wielded the Elements...
...it is you, who now control their power.
And it is you, who must defeat Discord!
Princess Celestia, you can count on...
Hold on a second!
Eternal chaos comes with
chocolate rain, you guys!
CHOCOLATE RAIN!
Don't listen to her, Princess.
We'd be honored to use
the Elements of Harmony again.
You can keep the Elements.
I'll take that case.
Have no fear, ponies.
I have total confidence that you
will be able to defeat Discord...
...with these.
Oh well. If anyone needs me...
...I'll be outside in the chocolate
puddles with a giant swizzle straw.
The Elements! They're gone!
That chamber is protected by
a powerful spell that only I can break.
This doesn't make sense...
"Make sense"? Oh, what fun
is there in making sense?
Discord! Show yourself!
Did you miss me, Celestia?
I've missed you.
It's quite lonely being encased in stone.
But you wouldn't know that, would you?
Because I don't turn ponies into stone!
Enough! What have you done
with the Elements of Harmony?
Well, I just borrowed them
for a teensy little while.
You'll never get away
with this, Discord!
Oh, I'd forgotten how grim
you can be, Celestia.
It's really quite boring.
Hey! Nopony insults the Princess!
Oh! You must be Rainbow Dash...
...famed for her loyalty ‒ the Element
of Harmony you represent.
That's right! I'll always
be loyal to the Princess!
We'll see about that.
I can't believe we're wasting our time
talking to a tacky window.
The beautiful Rarity, representing
the Element of Generosity...
...if I'm not mistaken.
So you know who we are. Big deal.
Oh, I know much more than
that, honest Applejack.
You seem to know our strengths too.
Yes, Twilight Sparkle.
And yours is the most powerful
and elusive element ‒ magic.
Fluttershy's is kindness and Pinkie Pie's
is the personal favorite of mine...
...laughter!
Pinkie!
He's standing on your head!
Stop stalling, Discord!
What have you done with
the Elements of Harmony?
Oh! So boring, Celestia. Really.
Fine. I'll tell you, but
I'll only tell you my way.
To retrieve your missing elements,
just make sense of this change of events.
Twists and turns are my master plan...
...then find the Elements
back where you began.
Can we go home now?
What do you reckon he meant?
"Twists and turns" and then
the "back where we started".
Twists and turns...
Twists and turns! That's it!
I bet Discord hid the Elements
in the palace labyrinth!
Good luck, my little ponies.
The fate of Equestria is in your hooves.
Thanks, Princess. We won't let you down.
We... We have to go in there?
Nope! Dopey Discord
forgot about these babies!
I'll just do a quick flyover and
we'll have the Elements in no time.
My wings!
Your horn!
My horn!
You... You should see the looks
on your faces. Priceless!
Give us our wings and horns back!
You'll get them back in good time.
I simply took them to ensure
there's no cheating.
You see, this is the first
rule of our game:
No flying and no magic.
The first rule?
The second rule is: everypony has to play
or the game is over.
And I win.
Good luck, everypony!
Never fear, girls. We have each other.
Yeah! Like Twilight said.
There's nothing we can't overcome
if we all stick together.
All right, girls! Let's do this.
Together!
Stay calm, girls!
Everypony head to the middle as fast as
you can and we'll regroup there.
-Moving out!
-See you in the center.
-Yeehaw!
-See you guys there!
What's that?! Who's there?! GIIIRLS!
What in tarnation?
Where am I?
Who are y'all?
The keepers of the grove of truth.
You may ask us...
...a one question:
Past, future or present.
But be warned...
...that the truth...
...may not always be pleasant.
Alright then. I don't trust
this place for the hill a' beans...
...but I got a real bad feelin'
about this feller Discord.
What's gonna come of this
here mission we're on?
For the answer you seek...
...go ahead! Take a peek.
I hope I'll never see you again!
Me too!
-Fine!
It's settled then.
No!
Our friendship... over?
It can't be true. It just can't!
That just can't be the truth.
When all the truth does...
...is make your heart ache...
...sometimes a lie is easier to take.
Applejack! Thank goodness.
I thought I heard voices over here.
Who were you talking to?
I was talkin' to, uh...
Nopony! Nopony whatsoever.
What?
Nothin'.
Come on. Uh, we best be goin'.
Did Applejack just...
Come on, Twilight.
Applejack wouldn't lie.
This is the greatest
balloon garden I've ever seen!
It's the first balloon garden
I've ever seen, but still...
Hey! What gives?
What's the matter, Pinkie Pie?
I thought you appreciated a good laugh.
It's different. They're
laughing *at* me.
It's hardly different.
Your friends laugh at you all the time.
My friends laugh *with* me, not at me.
Oh, really?
No! Stop it!
Stop laughing at me!
Oh, poor Pinkie Pie.
And here I thought
laughter made you happy.
Happy?
I don't think so.
Pinkie Pie! Are we glad to see you.
You are, huh? WHY? Need a good laugh?
Pinkie?
What do you suppose has her
so upset? It's not like her.
I didn't notice anythin'
strange about Pinkie.
Weird. Better pick up the pace before
the stress of this gets the better of all of us.
I was expecting an audience with
the Princess, not outdoor sports.
Oh my.
Welcome to your lucky day, Rarity.
You've found the one thing in Equestria
that could rival my face for sheer beauty.
What do you think? You like?
Yes... I like very much.
NO! No. I shan't succumb
to such fabulousness.
Must... get to the center...
to meet... the others...
MINE!!!
Well, Rarity...
It took forever, but it was worth it.
Who knew three little gemstones would turn out
to be this handsome HUNK of a diamond?
Now to get you home.
Rarity! Are we glad to see...
Why are you carrying
a humongous boulder?
What do you mean "boulder"?
This big, beautiful, bedazzling
rock is a DIAMOND!
And it's all mine.
Keep your envious little eyes off it!
I found it and it's mine,
fair and square!
Okay, I can do this. I can...
Oh! Wait a minute!
Butterflies? Wait! Don't leave me here!
Fluttershy.
Looks like you've been left behind
by your so-called friends, huh?
Oh, no. I'm certain they're
doing their best to find me.
Well, it must be so upsetting to know how
weak and helpless they think you are.
Not at all!
I *am* weak and helpless and
I appreciate their understanding.
Yes, well... surely it burns you up, I mean...
...that they're always
pointing out your flaws, right?
Not really. In fact...
I think I'm awfully lucky to have friends
who want me to be the best I can be.
Oh, for goodness's sake!
You've been kind for
far too long, my dear.
Time to be cruel!
Arrivederci!
Fluttershy! I'm so glad
to see your friendly face.
This awful labyrinth is
getting to everypony.
Oh, boo hoo hoo!
Why don't you wave your magic little horn
and make everything all right?
Oh, that's right. You can't.
You don't have one.
What is happening to my friends?
And what are YOU laughing at?!
Chocolate milk!
Little help here?
Thanks, Twilight.
-You're welcome...
-But don't get any ideas about my gem!
I know where you live.
I've got you now, Element.
I can see why you like these
clouds so much. Very plush.
Get off there and put 'em up!
C'mon, let's go!
Hey, I'm here to deliver a message.
I've got a message for you too!
Listen closely. This is important.
A weighty choice is yours to make ‒
The right selection or a big mistake.
If the wrong choice you choose to pursue,
The foundations of home will crumble without you.
Cloudsdale? Crumble... without me...
NO!!!
That box contains your wings.
You can take them and leave the game...
...or you can carry on aimlessly
wandering this maze. Your choice.
Must... find... Rainbow Dash...
As a team... we're unstoppable.
Rainbow Dash won't let us down.
Well, lookie there.
Rainbow Dash is flyin' away.
She's abandonin' us.
Now I know that's a lie.
How can it be?!
Well, well, well. Somepony broke
the "no wings, no magic" rule.
Game's over, my little ponies.
You didn't find your precious elements.
Looks like we might be due
for a big old storm of chaos.
Synced by Nathan2000
http://mlp.wikia.com/wiki/User:Nathan2000