The timber wolves are a-howlin'!
Eyup.
The Zap Apples are comin'!
Yay, the Zap Apples are comin'!
That's what I said.
Subbed and Synced by GrayJeager
http://grayjeager.blogspot.com
GrayJeager@gmail.com
Hey, silly goose!
Quit your gawkin' and move your caboose!
Ready, Granny!
- Ready for what?
- For makin' Zap Apple Jam!
Darn tootin'! It's time for some good
old-fashioned Zap Apple Jammin'!
Yes mam, I can't wait mam!
Wait for what?
To make Zap Apple Jam with you!
Of course!
Now I been doing this ever
since I was a little pony.
So be warned, pickle pear,
there's a whole mess steps in this process
and you got to get each one of them just right...
...or no Zap Apple Jam.
Take this.
Is this one of your gazillion secret herbal
ingredients for the Zap Apple Jam?
That there's a broom.
Now get sweepin', pipsqueak!
Now while you sweep, I'll get to...
Oh ponyfeathers!
Bet I'd forget my mane if it
wasn't attached to my head.
There's the Zap Apple leaves!
Right on schedule!
(Granny Smith sings the ABC's)
Well, howdy-doo there, Filthy Rich!
Hello, Mrs. Smith, did I hear right that there's
a Zap Apple harvest coming in a few days?
Four days, to be exact.
Excellent news!
And as usual, I get your first hundred jars?
'Course, Filthy.
I prefer Rich?
Oh, you poor, poor thing...
...having to make all that
Zap Apple Jam with Granny Smith.
Actually, I been looking forward to
making Zap Apple Jam for years!
I'm not talking about the jam,
I'm talking about Granny Smith!
You must be sooo embarassed.
What do ya mean?
You know, with all her silly ways,
how she forgets things...
...and makes you wear these
ridiculous costumes?
Granny said that the water needs-
Thank goodness you're here on the farm and
not in town where everypony could see you.
Don't worry.
Your secret is safe with me.
"Silly ways"?
Thank you kindly, Filthy!
Shake a leg there, slowpoke!
We got a gaggle's worth of goods
to gather before the harvest.
Come on!
Gonna make Zap Apple Jam, oopsie ooh!
Gatherin' the goodies now, oopdie hee!
Singin' and dancin', diddleye ooh, flippity floo my darlin'!
They don't make 'em like they used to.
Hey, you bite it, you buy it!
Why hello bees, Beatrice, Beecher!
You've all been busy little bees, haven't you?
Granny, isn't there a less
silly way to get the honey?
Isn't this just precious?
Please stop!
And it is perfect for makin'
our Zap Apple Jam!
Stop it, Granny!
Granny, please!
Those ponies over there are watchin' me!
What?
Are those fillies your friends?
Hello, Half-pint's friends!
Hi, Granny Smith!
Hi, Half-pint!
What dolls.
Why, when I was little,
ponies didn't come that purdy.
Are we done shopping, Granny?
'Cause I'd like to get back to the farm, fast.
Hold on, snellybelly.
I got my honey, gooey-goo!
Got my honey, gooey-ooh!
Got my honey, iddley-hoo!
And by capturing the whole sale market,
purchasing in bulk and slashing all prices
we undermine every other gift market in town.
And that's how Rich's Barnyard Bargains
became the cornerstone of retail in Ponyville.
Well, thank you, Mr. Filthy- I mean, Mr. Rich...
...what a wonderful day of sharing!
And thank you for being a part of
Family Appreciation Day!
Now, let's see who will be bringing in a family member
for next Monday's Family Appreciation Day...
Oh! Apple Bloom!
But Miss Cheerilee,
Monday is Zap Apple harvest day!
And Applejack and Big Macintosh
will be too busy to come and speak.
Well, is there anypony else
in your family that could-
Miss Cheerilee! Apple Bloom's Granny Smith
isn't working harvest...
...she could come.
Oh!
But, uh, no, that wouldn't-
That's a splendid idea, Diamond Tiara!
Apple Bloom, you shall bring in
Granny Smith on Monday.
Have a great weekend, everypony!
Granny Smith?
Come Monday?
I'll be the laughing stock of Ponyville!
I'm sorry, Apple Bloom,
I already told you that
we just can't take a break from
harvest to come to your school.
You know what'll happen.
I know... after the fifth day,
the Zap Apples disappear...
Look! The third sign!
Right on time!
Hot diggity!
Alright, you lazy daisies,
cool your caboose!
I'm sorry, Apple Bloom,
but don't you fret.
Granny Smith's got no shortage
of entertainin' stories to tell.
I know.
That's what I'm worried about...
I'll be embarrassed, shamed,
disgraced, mortified, humiliate-
What are you, a dictionary?
Snap out of it,
we're here to help you!
After all, we are the
Cutie Mark Crusaders.
We'll figure out a way to
postpone your presentation.
But how?
All this worry is makin' me sick!
Sick?
That's it!
C'mon!
Ten-hut!
Now listen here, troops!
I don't want any whinin', or cryin',
or crackin' under pressure!
Do I make myself clear?
Court-martial!
Stay still, Apple Bloom!
You have to look sick!
Hey, this is hot!
What in the hayseed is going on
in there, silly billy?
Oh, Granny Smith! We were
just about to come get you!
Apple Bloom's sick!
Looks like she may have
to stay home all week!
Perfect as a Piccadilly pear!
Now what?
It's already almost sundown!
Tomorrow is Sunday and I only have
one more day to figure something out!
Hey!
Look!
That's the fourth sign!
The Zap Apples have appeared!
And that gives me an idea!
We can't move Family Appreciation Day,
so let's move harvest day instead!
They don't look... quite ripe.
Harvesting apples early
never hurt an apple.
I don't know... Zap Apple trees
aren't like normal apple trees.
They're magic.
How different can they be?
Well if we can't buck 'em,
let's just pick 'em!
Any other bright ideas?
Granny Smith, it's Miss Cheerilee!
Apple Bloom said you
wanted to speak with me?
Hello?
Granny Smi-
Well hello there!
Howdydoo!
Hi... Granny Smith...
is everything okay?
Of course it is!
Why wouldn't it be?
Excuse me, pickles always
give me the hiccups!
I need to tell you that I can't make
the presentation on Monday after all!
Oh no, is that so?
No doubts about it!
I gotta shear the flowers
and water the sheep!
I mean, I have to water the flowers
and shear the sheep!
That's too bad.
We can reschedule.
Where am I?
Well howdy, Miss Cheerilee!
You window shopping?
No, you asked me to come
here to tell me that you
wouldn't be making it to
Family Appreciation Day?
Fiddlesticks! I wouldn't miss it
for all the tea in Canterlot!
- But, didn't you just say...
- See you Monday!
I can't believe she woke up from her nap.
She never wakes up from her nap!
I wish I could just run off and hide!
Well you can't run off...
but maybe somepony else can!
The Zap Apple harvest has begun!
And tomorrow we'll be making up
some Zap Apple Jam!
Miss Granny Smith?
Telegram.
Well, bust my buttons.
Uncle Apple Strudel wants me to pay him a visit.
And you can just make the 8am train.
I already packed you a bag!
Well that was considerate.
But don't you worry, flibbertigibbet!
I'll be back in time to make that jam!
That train ride takes all day.
I'm safe.
For today's Family Appreciation Day
we are pleased to welcome Granny Smith.
Apple Bloom?
Is Granny Smith here?
I'm sorry, Miss Cheerilee,
but she got called out of town
on account of a family emergency...
Well howdy, my little ponies!
Howdy, y'all! I'm as happy as a pig
in a fresh mudpile to be here!
What are you doing here?
Did you miss the train?
No, it came.
And Uncle Apple Strudel was on it.
Ooooooh, noogie noogie noggie!
I can't wait to hear
Granny Smith's presentation...
...if she can remember any of it.
Long ago, when I was a little pony...
...things were very different here in Ponyville...
...'cause there was no Ponyville!
That's right, my little ponies.
Me and my family were pilgrim pony folk
back when I was a little filly.
We ventured far and wide
collecting new seeds and sellin' them on.
But my pa was the finest seed collector in all of Equestria.
Then, one day, the Smith family
found themselves in the most brilliant,
most grand, most magnificent of all cities.
A place called... Canterlot.
Why, I bet your hooves to hindquarters that
I had never seen anything like it before nor since.
And as if the beauty of that city
wasn't enough, suddenly, she appeared...
Princess Celestia, the most regal of all ponies.
When lo and behold, she stopped and
look at my pa's seed collection.
Then Princess Celestia saw that
we were plumb-tuckered
and hankerin' to find our forever home.
And bein' a royal Princess and all,
she knew exactly the place for us
to lay down our stakes.
My pa gave the Princess a mighty thanks.
We quickly found that land near the Everfree Forest
and we built our first home.
Next, we planted our first orchards.
But an orchard don't grow overnight...
and we were getting mighty short on food.
Now mind you, we were
cautioned about the forest
and we knew that it was not fit to enter.
But I knew there was critters livin' there
so there must be somethin' to eat.
It was dark and musty
and I won't lie, it was scary.
But every inch was covered in plant life.
And before I knew it wasn't I standin'
in front of the most incredible...
...apple trees!
I had never seen anything before
this kind of colorful fruit!
I started picking apples quick as a whip!
I turned, and there before me stood...
...the timber wolves!
I'd never run so fast in my life.
I did the only thing I could think of...
My pa and I planted those special apple seeds
and before our eyes they grew like wildfire.
Well, we had full grown trees faster
than you could say lickety split.
Then each year, I paid close attention to
the signs of the Zap Apple special harvesting times.
How the weather affects the Everfree Forest
how the timber wolves howl when
the Zap Apples first start growing
and how they zapped away if
you didn't pick 'em all in one day!
And the fruits of our labor were
the best fruit we ever tasted.
Soon enough I was mixing up batches of Zap Apple Jam.
Just like harvestin' the Zap Apples had its special rules
so did makin' Zap Apple Jam!
I learned that you gotta be extra friendly with the bees
otherwise their honey won't taste rightly sweet to
mix in with the Zap Apples.
Who'd'a thought that glass jars needed talking to?
Or that Zap Apples like pink polka dots?
But magic is as magic does.
Just funny that way.
Then ponies started comin' to our farm from far and wide
just to get a taste of my Zap Apple Jam.
Some of them decided to stay, like Stinkin' Rich...
...Diamond Tiara's great grandfather.
Matter of fact, the first thing he ever sold
was my Zap Apple Jam.
And before we knew it, we had
ourselves a nice little town.
Bustling with all kinds of ponies.
And that is how Ponyville was founded.
Thank you kindly, little ponies.
Now now, let's settle down.
So if it weren't for you and the Zap Apples,
Ponyville wouldn't even exist?!
Darn tootin', little filly!
If it weren't for my Granny Smith,
your daddy wouldn't have Barnyard Bargains.
But-
But she's just a... kooky old lady!
She is not a kooky old lady!
She is the most amazing pony
in all of Ponyville!
I think this is the best Zap Apple Jam I've tasted yet!
Must because YOU had something
to do with it, Apple Bloom.
You betcha.
Apple Bloom is one humdinger of a Zap Apple Jammer!
I am?
So I take it Family Appreciation Day went well?
Did it?
My Granny Smith is super special!
I just forgot that for a little while.
Aw, don't fret.
I forget things all the time.
Now, I'll getcha...
...somethin'.
Who wants to help Granny sing to the water?
We do!
Diamond Tiara?
But dad!