Attention, everypony! Attention!
The official Rainbow Dash Fan Club will come to order.
Let's get right down to our first order of business.
I motion that Rainbow Dash be declared the most awesome pony in Ponyville.
I second the motion, and might I add that if you looked up the word 'awesome' in the dictionary,
there would be a picture of Rainbow Dash.
I object!
I think the word 'awesome' is played out!
Rainbow Dash deserves better. I motion that we declare her the most stupendous pony!
'Stupendous'? Is that the best you've got?
I motion that we declare her... wonderiffic!
- Astonishing!
- Breathtaking!
- Astounding!
- Bedazzling!
What about super-ultra-extreme-awesomazing?
All in favor of declaring Rainbow Dash the most 'super-ultra-extra-ah-whatever-you-said' pony in all of Ponyville, say 'aye'!
Aye!
Subbed and synced by GrayJeager
http://www.youtube.com/user/JeagerGray
http://grayjeager.blogspot.com
What a beautiful day.
There's nothing like a dip in the clouds to make a pegasus feel super relaxed.
Help! Help!
Looks like my sky swim will have to wait!
I'm Rainbow Dash, and I'm here to rescue you!
What's with this crowd?
Uh, thanks everypony.
It was really no big deal.
To me it was! You're my hero, Rainbow Dash!
That Rainbow Dash sure is something.
Something special.
Oh no! There's something wrong with the baby!
She's not cheering for everypony's favorite hero, Rainbow Dash!
There just aren't enough words in the dictionary to describe Rainbow Dash's awesomeness.
I can think of a few new words.
And I bet 'modest' is not one of them.
No, but she is kinda awesome.
Never fear, your friendly neighborhood Rainbow Dash is here!
We'd be lost without you!
You're our hero, Rainbow Dash!
Rainbow Dash!
I can't hear you!
Rainbow Dash! Rainbow Dash! Rainbow Dash! Rainbow Dash! Rainbow Dash! Rainbow Dash!
Call me silly, but I think this whole hero thing might be going to Rainbow Dash's head.
You may be right, silly.
And then, I zoomed into the well. I knew it would be dark and dangerous, but I didn't let that stop me.
Danger's my middle name. Rainbow 'Danger' Dash.
Thinking back on it, I acted pretty awesomely heroic that day.
That day.
Awesomely heroic that day and awesomely arrogant ever since.
Hey, Applejack. How would you like to be immortalized as my friend?
Immorta what?
Are you taking notes?
Yup! I've been hoof-picked by Rainbow Dash herself, to write her autobiography!
Autobiographies are supposed to be written by the pony they are about.
Maybe for your normal, run-of-the-mill ponies.
But I'm far too busy saving lives to stop and write.
That's why I hired Spike as my ghost writer.
Spike's a ghost!
Anyway...
Spike here writes down everything I say.
Don't you, Spike?
'Don't you Spike...'
Got it!
This way, I can stay focused on performing those acts of bravery that nopony else has the guts to perform.
Yep, it takes guts. But it also takes brains.
And sometimes a big lunch and a nap.
Being a hero is surely not for everypony, but I'm up to the challenge.
There you go.
Someday, I wanna be just like you!
Aim high, kid, but don't aim for the impossible.
Help! Help!
Don't you think you should go and help?
Yeah, yeah. I've got a good ten seconds to spare. Just a couple more.
The tension is unbearable.
Will Rainbow Dash make it on time?
Holy turnips, that pony came out of nowhere!
I've never seen such bravery in all my life!
That's right! Ponyville has a new hero.
A mysterious mare that has done well by our fair city today.
I dub this new masked hero 'The Mysterious Mare-Do-Well'!
'Mare-Do-Well', huh?
Well that mare would do well to stay outta my way!
Ponyville's only got room for one hero, and that hero is me!
Never fear, your friendly neighborhood Rainbow-
Excuse me, do you think you could skip your catchphrase and just hurry up and save us?!
Fine! Picky, picky.
Thank you mare to, well um-
I can't believe it.
Mare-Do-Well is stronger than me?
Well, a hero is more than just muscle. And she's gonna learn that the hard way.
Never fear, your friendly neighborhood whoa!
Never fear-
I'm coming... hold on.
Look!
Look out for the-
Watch out for falling-
On your left! Argh! Your other left!
Here you go, safe and sound.
Well, Mare-Do-Well, or should I call you 'Mare-Do-Slow'?
You're gonna have to pick up the pace if you wanna compete with me, 'cause I move like lightning.
Actually, she saved all of us! We owe her our lives!
Okay. She's strong, fast, and somehow knows what's gonna happen ahead of time.
I've gotta step up my game.
If the dam breaks, the whole town will be flooded!
Looks like Ponyville needs a hero!
Easy peasy.
My game is officially back on.
If only somepony were here to pat me on the back...
Well, I'll do it myself.
Heeeelp!
You?!
I suppose you want me to thank-
You gotta be kidding me.
Lemme get this straight.
She's strong, she's agile, and she's magic?
How do I compete with that?
Wait a minute. I do have a leg up on her.
And that leg is... wings!
Take that, Mare-Do-Well!
Oh, for the love of pete.
Gotta hand it to the girl, that Mare-Do-Well sure can pull off some pretty heroic feats.
I must say I was impressed by that spell she used to fix the dam.
Seems like something like that would take quite a bit of study.
She really cares about everypony's safety.
Have you seen her costume? It is to die for! If you ask me she's a hero of fashion.
And she's modest and humble.
She lets her actions speak for themselves. Gotta admire that.
I don't have to admire that! I don't think she's all that great!
- She's... great.
- I didn't say that.
Sounds like somepony's jealous.
Who, me?
- Rainbow Dash is jealous.
- Don't write that, Spike!
Correction: Rainbow Dash is very jealous.
Fine! Laugh all you want, but I'll be the one laughing when I prove to you all that I'm just as good-
no, that I'm a better hero than Mare-Do-Well!
No sign of trouble here, darnit.
Buses and baby carriages are always careening down this hill.
Where is an out-of-control vehicle when you need one?!
There are absolutely no freak natural disasters going on anywhere!
How am I supposed to prove myself when everything's so normal and safe?
Hold it right there, Granny Smith! You don't have to pretend with me.
I can see that you're in way over your head here.
Eh, what's that?
You're putting on a brave face, I get it. But you don't have to anymore.
I'll help you cross the street!
Actually I can cross the street just fine!
Don't worry! You're in extremely... capable... hooves!
Back off!
Here we are! Safe and sound.
A good and heroic citizen deserves a little recognition, don't you think?
I didn't wanna cross the street in the first place!
Somepony's in trouble!
You'd better let me handle this, ma'am!
For your own safety, I must ask you to stand back!
Oh, brother.
Ta-dah!
Uh... thanks.
How would you describe what I just did? Would you say I was amazing?
Aren't you milking this a bit?
Please, just answer the question!
Was I, or was I not, amazing?
- No, you're amazing alright. An amazingly-
- Oh look !
Another great feat of heroism! I have just saved that grass!
From what?
From weeds!
Weeds that were attempting to eat this lawn!
Lame.
Whatever.
Who am I kidding?
All anypony talks about is Mare-Do-Well this, and Mare-Do-Well that!
What about me? How could everypony forget about me so easily?
I mean... have I changed?
Same sleek body. Same flowing mane. Same spectacular hooves.
Nope, I'm still awesome.
They're wrong. But... then... why am I all alone?
I hate being all alone.
- Hey Rainbow Dash!
- I knew it!
No need to apologize, squirt. Anypony could make a mistake.
Mistake? What mistake?
Wait a minute. Why are you here?
To invite you to join us.
We're heading off to the thank you parade for Ponyville's greatest hero, Mare-Do-Well.
No! No way! Can't you see I wanna be alone? I love being alone.
Oh, ok. See you later then.
Yeah, right, like I'm gonna thank her.
Thank you, Mare-Do-Well, whoever you are, for ruining e-
Hey squirt! Wait up!
Welcome to Ponyville's first, but surely not last, thank you parade, in honor of our city's greatest hero,
the mysterious Mare-Do-Well!
The mysterious Mare-Do-Well, huh?
So what are you hiding? Let's see how mysterious you are without that mask!
What the hay?
I got you now!
Alright, Miss Mysterious! Mystery...
... solved!
P-P-P-Pinkie?! What the-th-th-huh?!
Twilight?!
Applejack?!
There were three of you?
Yup, we all played Mare-Do-Well at different times.
I stopped the carriage bus with these babies.
Bucky McGillygutty and Kicks McGee.
I saved the construction workers with my Pinkie Sense.
Sorry!
It's alright.
And I used my magic to fix the dam.
Ooh, ooh! And I did the flyby afterwards.
I made the costumes. Fabulous if I do say so myself.
I don't understand.
Why?
Don't you want me to be a hero?
Of course we want you to be a hero.
But a real hero doesn't brag.
I guess I did start to brag a little.
A little?!
Okay, a lot.
Celebrating your accomplishments is natural. But...
Rubbin' them in everypony's face is not.
Yeah, the only thing that should be rubbed in anypony's face is chocolate cake.
I think we're getting off topic here.
What we're trying to say is, it's great to be really good at something,
but it's important to act with grace and humility.
That makes loads more sense.
Yeah. You're right.
And I guess I should've also acted with grace and humility when others outshine me.
Like Mare-Do-Well.
Sounds like you've got a letter to write to Princess Celestia.
Already got it covered. As your ghost writer, I've already penned a letter to the Princess.
That's nice of you, Spike, but I really wanna write this letter myself.
Come on, I wrote the whole thing already!
Okay, let's hear it.
- Dear Princess Cel-
- Look out! It's a real ghost!